♪ 噗 ♪
♪ Pum ♪
♪ pum ♪
♪ Penelope ♪ ♪ 誰是 Penelope ？ ♪
♪ Penelope ♪ ♪ who is Penelope? ♪
♪ 想象一個步伐像母虎的女孩 ♪
♪ Picture a girl who walks with the rhythm of a lady tiger ♪
♪ 想象一個說話像蜜蜂般甜美的女孩 ♪
♪ picture a girl who talks with the sweetness of a honey bee ♪
♪ 想象一個你永遠無法忘記的女孩 ♪
♪ picture a girl your mind could never dismiss ♪
♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪
♪ this is Penelope ♪ ♪ this is Penelope ♪
♪ Penelope ♪♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪
♪ Penelope ♪ ♪ this is Penelope ♪
♪ 天使製造者計劃她的那一天 ♪
♪ the day the angel-makers planned her ♪
♪ 她讓整個宇宙都沸騰了 ♪
♪ she set the universe abuzz ♪
♪ 沒有人能理解她 ♪
♪ there is no way to understand her ♪
♪ 事實上唯一懂她的人就是 Penelope ♪
♪ in fact the only one who does is Penelope ♪
♪ 誰是 Penelope ？ ♪
♪ who is Penelope? ♪
♪ Penelope ♪♪ 誰是 Penelope ？ ♪
♪ Penelope ♪ ♪ who is Penelope? ♪
♪ 想象一個生活像瘋狂魔術師的女孩 ♪
♪ Picture a girl whose life is as crazy as a mad magician ♪
♪ 想象一個心像自由鳥般難以捉摸的女孩 ♪
♪ picture a girl whose heart is elusive as a bird is free ♪
♪ 想象一個你心中的幸福化身 ♪
♪ picture a girl who's your conception of bliss ♪
♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪
♪ this is Penelope ♪ ♪ this is Penelope ♪
♪ Penelope ♪♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪
♪ Penelope ♪ ♪ this is Penelope ♪
金庫確實從堅硬的花崗岩中被炸出
The vaults literally blasted out of the solid granite
曼哈頓島的花崗岩。
of Manhattan island.
是的，先生們，
就像我那位蘇格蘭老祖父
Yes, gentlemen, as my old Scottish grandfather
可能會說，
“把你的錢放在我們這裏
might have said, "your money is safer with us
比交給尼斯湖水怪本人守護還要安全。”
than if it were guarded by the loch Ness monster herself."
現在，請隨我進行政套間。
And now if you will follow me into the executive suite.
哦，希望您不介意。
Oh, I hope you don't mind.
哦，塞雷娜小姐。
真是個好聽的名字。
Oh, miss Serena. What a sweet name.
謝謝。
Thank you.
我認爲名字對性格有很大影響。
I think names have a great influence on character.
- 難道不是嗎？- 嗯，怎麼說？
- Don"t you? - Well, how's that?
名叫塞雷娜的小姐應該沉着而寧靜。
A lady named miss Serena ought to be calm and serene.
- 你是嗎？ - 我盡力而爲。
- Are you? - Well, I try to be.
那就好，
因爲這是搶劫。
That's good, because this is a stickup.
現在，呃，別動。
Now, ah, don't move.
別把腳放到那個警報按鈕上
And don't put your foot on that alarm button
否則我就不得不開槍。
or I shall be forced to blast you.
親愛的，把那些好看的新的500美元鈔票捆給我。
Dearie, hand me those nice new stacks of $500 bills.
更多。
More.
哦。
Ooh.
那些印着格羅弗·克利夫蘭頭像的鈔票是什麼？1000美元嗎？
What are those bills with dear grover Cleveland's picture
也給我一把那種。
on them? $1000 bills?
讓我也來一把那種。
Let me have a handful of those too.
哦，還有一件事。
Oh, one more thing.
女士洗手間怎麼走？
Which way is the ladies' room?
謝謝你，親愛的。
你幫了大忙。
Thank you, dearie. You've been very helpful.
啦啦啦！
Ra-ra-ra!
爲啥要三呼？不！
Three cheers for what? =no!
搶了！
R-robbed!
被搶了？有人快去叫 Elcott 先生。
Robbed? Someone call Mr. Elcott.
是誰幹的？指出來。
Who did it? Point him out.
大家往後退。
Stand back, everybody.
不是他。是位女士。
Not him. Lady.
- 老年女士。 - 你能描述她嗎？
- Old lady. - Can you describe her?
- 老，老... - 冷靜點，冷靜！
- Old, old... - Calm down, calm down!
放輕鬆。 - 老...
Relax. -Old...
快，放開電子門。
Come on, release the electronic doors.
馬上， Elcott 先生。
At once, Mr. Elcott.
好了，女士，舉起手出來。
Alright, lady, come out with your hands up.
有槍！那可怕的老奶奶有槍！
A gun! That horrible old lady's got a gun!
在這座腐敗的城市裏沒地方是安全的。
A person isn't safe any place in this rotten city.
你先來。我還沒結婚呢。
You first. I'm not even married.
我找不到那個按鈕， Elcott 先生。
I couldn't find the button, Mr. Elcott.
Elcott 先生！ Elcott 先生！
Mr. Elcott! Mr. Elcott!
他們把她困在女廁所裏了。
They've trapped her in the ladies' room.
好了，小老太太，
您要出來嗎
Alright, little old lady, are you coming out
還是我們要進去？
or are we coming in?
沒有動靜。
Nothing.
你有一枚一角硬幣嗎？
Do you have a dime?
出於對您年紀的尊重，女士
In deference to your years, madam
我勸您別做傻事。
I urge you not to do anything foolish.
- 沒有。 - 我不明白。
- Nothing. - I don't get it.
我想我開始明白了。
I think I'm beginning to.
有人丟了件外套！
Someone lost a coat!
那個穿黃套裝的女人！她在哪？
That dame in a yellow suit! Where is she?
- 走吧！ - 快走，夥計們，出去！
- Let's go! - Come on, men, get out!
請接伯格多夫·古德曼（Bergdorf Goodman）。
Bergdorf Goodman, please.
出租車！
Taxi!
你怎麼樣？
How are you?
出了什麼事？
What seems to be the trouble?
市聯邦銀行發生搶劫。
Stickup at the city federal bank.
想象一下！
Imagine!
五名匪徒，攜帶機關槍和催淚瓦斯。
Five bandits with machine guns and tear gas.
不！
No!
他們搶走了超過十三萬美元！
Got away with over 130,000 bucks!
竟有那麼多？
As much as that?
天哪。
Good gracious.
Elcott 先生？
Mr. Elcott?
恭喜，你剛剛打破了世界紀錄。
Congratulations, you've just broken the world's record.
開業當天就被搶。
Robbed the same day you opened.
把這個瘋子扔出去！
Throw this nut out!
他不是瘋子。
他是警察中尉。
He's not a nut. He's a police lieutenant.
聽起來不像個了不起的警察中尉。
He doesn't sound like much of a police lieutenant.
你看起來也不像個很有派頭的銀行行長。
And you don't look like much of a bank president.
還有一條好看的瘦腿。
你注意到了嗎？
And a good bony leg. Did you notice?
爲了保衛我的銀行我丟了一條褲子。
I lost my trouser defending my bank.
本來不必如此
Something that wouldn't have been necessary
如果警方及時到位。
had the police been on the job.
好了，好了， Elcott 先生，
您弄反了。
Now, now, Mr. Elcott, you've got it backwards.
先有銀行案，然後纔是警察的事。
First, there is a bank job, then there is a police job.
你能別這麼大聲嗎？
這對生意不好。
Do you mind lowering your voice? It's bad for business.
進來吧。
Come inside.
你應該在離開之前就想過這事
You should have thought of that before you left
那些散放着的500美元和1000美元的鈔票。
all those $500 and $1000 bills lying around.
那是開業促銷的點子。
It was a promotional idea for the opening.
那種面額的紙幣不容易流通。
Bank notes of that denomination aren't readily negotiable.
我們有所有的序列號。
We have all the serial numbers.
我想
這會有點困難
I guess it would be kind of tough
想把1000美元鈔票在自動售貨機裏換成零鈔。
trying to break $1000 bill in an automat.
是啊，但如果他們能，
Yeah, but if they could,
你能想象1000美元全是五分硬幣嗎？
can you imagine 1000 bucks worth of nickels?
我覺得這個畫面挺好笑的。
I think it's a funny image.
你覺得重大盜竊有趣？
You find grand larceny amusing?
你太緊張了。
過於緊張。
You're tense. You're much too tense.
這對消化很不好。
放鬆。
Very bad for the digestion. Relax.
保險公司，
讓他們緊張去吧。
The insurance company, let them be tense.
他們得賠償你的損失。
They have to make good your losses.
我關心的是我們的聲譽受損。
I'm concerned with our loss of prestige.
這種事會導致公衆失去信心。
A thing like this could cause the public to lose confidence.
嗯，我真想不通爲什麼。
Well, now, I can't imagine why.
如果我是警察中尉，
我會去找
If I were a police, lieutenant, I think I'd be out looking
那位紅髮女郎穿着黃色套裝，帶着6萬美元。
for $60,000 carried by a redhead in a yellow suit.
機率大概四十比一
The odds are, like, 40 to 1
那個紅髮女郎早就換下那套衣服了。
that the redhead is no longer modeling that particular number.
給你看， Elcott 先生。
就在影片裏。
Here you are, Mr. Elcott. Right here on film.
記錄了2點到3點之間發生的一切。
Everything that happened between 2:00 and 3:00.
搶劫發生在2:47。
The robbery took place at 2:47.
我們總是拍攝新銀行開業的前幾天。
We always film the first few days of a new bank's operation.
- 有助於消除問題。 - 真是天助我也。
- Helps eliminate the bugs. - Well, talk about dumb luck.
羅斯柴爾德，把這些拿到實驗室去。
Rothschild, get these down to the lab.
我們今晚去看電影。
We're going to the movies tonight.
把 Elcott 太太叫來。
她要是沒在家
Get me Mrs. Elcott. If she's not at home
Elcott 太太在這， Mannix 醫生。
Mrs. Elcott is here, Dr. Mannix.
請她進來。
Send her in.
- 下午好，Gregory。 - 晚上好。
- Good afternoon, Gregory. - Good evening.
哦，Gregory，我非常抱歉。
我就是忍不住。
Oh, Gregory, I'm terribly sorry. I just couldn't help it.
事情一直在發生。
Things kept happening.
哦，感覺真好。
Oh, that feels good.
我度過了這麼一天！
I've had such a day!
希望是美好的一天？嗯。
Good day, I hope? Mm.
不再逃避現實或試圖逃跑了嗎？
No more escapism or attempt to run away from reality?
有點兒奔，也有點兒逃避。
A little running, yes. Little escaping too.
嗯。你今天下午看起來真美
Hm. Well, you look so beautiful this afternoon
我會試着原諒你的。
I'll try to forgive it.
Gregory，你以前從沒說過這樣的話。
Gregory, you've never said anything like that before.
“春天裏，少年幻想？”
"In the spring, a young man's fancy?"
Penelope，我並沒有愛上你，
Penelope, I am not in love with you,
你也沒有愛上我。
nor are you in love with me.
不過根據你目前的分析，你可能會這麼想。
Although at this stage of your analysis, you may think so.
哦，我不認爲我愛上了你。
Oh, I don't think I'm in love with you.
哦，你，你不覺得你愛上了我？
Oh, you, you don't think you're in love with me?
沒有。這從未在我腦海中出現。
No. Never entered my mind.
怎麼了？你失望了嗎？
Why? Are you disappointed?
一點也不！
Not in the least!
事實上，我鬆了口氣。哦。
In fact, I'm relieved. Oh.
那很好。
That's good.
所以你過了有趣的一天，是嗎？
So you had an interesting day, huh?
想談談嗎？
Care to talk about it?
嗯，讓我想想。
Well, let's see.
今天早上我去購物了
This morning I went shopping
然後我去了現代藝術博物館。
and then I went to the museum of modern art.
那裏有個極好的新展覽。
They have a marvelous new exhibit there.
然後我在，嗯，廣場大飯店吃了午飯。
Then I had lunch at the, uh, Plaza.
棕櫚庭。
The palm court.
班尼迪克蛋。
Eggs Benedict.
然後，在三點前幾分鐘
And then, a few minutes before 3 o'clock
我搶劫了我丈夫的銀行。
I stuck up my husband's bank.
你睡着了嗎？
Are you asleep?
不，我...
No, I...
你沒有聯想。你——你知道嗎？
You're not associating. You-you realize that?
你是什麼意思？
How do you mean?
我是說，你說你去購物。
I mean, you said you went shopping.
你去了博物館，你吃了午飯。
You went to the museum, you had lunch.
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
然後你說了些完全無關的話。
And then you said something entirely irrelevant.
Gregory，不是我不聯想，而是你。
Gregory, it's you who's not associating.
我只是說我搶了我丈夫的銀行。
All I said was I stuck up my husband's bank.
你又說了一遍。但你不可能那樣做。
You said it again. But you couldn't possibly.
你怎麼知道？
How do you know?
因爲我當了你三年的分析師。
Because I've been your analyst for three years.
我知道你能做什麼
I know what you're capable of
也知道你做不到什麼。
and I know what you're not capable of.
你想打賭嗎？
Would you like to bet?
我在精神病學界的聲譽
My reputation in psychiatry
對你願意拿出的任何東西。
against anything you care to put up.
這些夠嗎？
Will this be enough?
那是什麼？
What's that?
嗯，我想那叫贓款。
Well, I think it's called the loot.
贓——款？
The-the loot?
佩—— Penelope，你能...
P-Penelope, would-would you...
所以你認爲你搶了銀行，是嗎？
So you think you robbed a bank, huh?
嗯，我一直這麼說。
Hm, I've been saying that.
然後我去了伯格多夫，買了這套新裝。
Then I went over to Bergdorf's and bought this new outfit.
你喜歡嗎？
Do you like it?
Penelope，你是要我相信
Penelope, do you expect me to believe
你搶了你丈夫的銀行
that you robbed your husband's bank
然後輕鬆地去伯格多夫
and went blithely off to Bergdorf's
把贓款花在裙子和貂皮上？
and spent the loot on dresses and minks?
- 當然不會。 - 那就好。
- Of course not. - Well, thank goodness.
不，我不會花贓款。
No, I wouldn't spend stolen money.
我有賒賬賬戶。
I have a charge account.
你仍然堅持你搶了銀行。
You still insist you robbed a bank.
那你怎麼可能呢？
Now how could you?
Gregory，這很簡單...
Gregory, it's very simple...
拜託，我——我不想聽。
我——不想聽。
Please, I-I don't wanna hear. I-I don't want to hear it.
我我我我不想聽這件事。
I-I-I-I don't wanna hear about it.
哦，當然，那會使你成爲事後從犯。
Oh, of course, that would make you an accessory after the fact.
Gregory，對不起。
別不高興。
Gregory, I'm sorry. Don't be upset.
我們就忘了我曾提起過這事。
We'll just forget I ever mentioned it.
我們什麼都不會忘的。
We're not going to forget about anything.
你——你搶了多少錢？
H-how much did you get?
太可怕了！
That's horrible!
是啊，但我剛數過了。
Yeah, but I just counted it.
只有略多於6萬美元。
It's only a little over 60,000.
所以也就只有一半那麼可怕。
So it's only half as horrible.
Penelope，你的生活就像一場瘋狂的魔術表演一樣不可思議。
Penelope, nobody can just walk into a bank
並且通過開口要來 $60,000。
and pick up $60,000 by asking for it.
當然可以。前提是你有槍。
Of course, you can. If you have a gun.
你根本沒有槍！
You don't own a gun!
哦，Gregory，你總是這麼樂觀。
Oh, Gregory, you're always so positive.
你以爲這是什麼？
What do you think this is?
哦，對不起。我不知道它是上膛的。
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't know it was loaded.
我是在哪家五金店買的。
I bought it in the five and dime.
Penelope，這對你的治療非常不利。
Penelope, this is very bad for your therapy.
對不起，Gregory。
I'm sorry, Gregory.
在你的分析中，我顯然在某處……
Somewhere in your analysis, I have obviously...
錯過了一個重要的線索。
Passed up a vital clue.
現在我——我要你從頭再告訴我一次
Now I-I want you to tell me again from the beginning
關於你第一次拿走東西的那次。
about the first time that you took something.
你是說偷東西，不是嗎？
You mean stole something, don't you?
Gregory，我們不如面對現實。
Gregory, we might as well face it.
我是個偷竊狂。
I'm a kleptomaniac.
我拒絕從臨牀上接受那個詞。
I refuse to accept that word clinically.
那第一次是什麼時候？
Now what was the first time?
嗯，真正的第一次……
Well, the very first time...
是在我大學的最後一週。
Was my last week in college.
我盛裝打扮去參加畢業舞會，
I was all dressed up for the senior prom
這時 Klobb 教授過來了。
when Professor Klobb came by.
Klobb 教授教人類學404。
Professor Klobb taught anthropology 404.
他說他想在實驗室裏給我看一些照片，
And he said he'd like to show me some pictures
是關於 Okokos 部落的。
of the Okokos tribe in his laboratory.
他說 Okokos 有些非常奇怪的習俗。
He said the Okokos had some very strange customs.
嗯，他們確實有，
Well, they certainly did,
但也不比 Klobb 教授的奇怪。
but no stranger than Professor Klobb's.
哦！哦！
Oh! Oh!
哦！
Oh!
抱歉。
Sorry.
哦！
Oh!
啊！
Ah!
起初我並沒有注意到，
I didn't notice it at first,
但我的手裏有了東西。
but there was something in my hand.
不知怎的，在我們的課間裏，
Somehow, sometime during our session
在原始人類學那節課上，
in primitive anthropology,
我抓住了 Klobb 教授的
I had grabbed hold of Professor Klobb's
懷錶鏈，鑲着鑽石的。
watch fob, diamond-studded.
我本來可以把它送回去，當然，
I could have sent it back, of course,
但我決定就留着它，
but I decided I'd just keep it
作爲奧科科斯部落那些奇怪習俗的紀念。
in memory of the strange customs of the Okokos tribe.
這就是我犯罪生涯的開始。
So that's where I began my life of crime.
幾乎是偶然的。
Practically by accident.
下一次事件是什麼時候？
When was the next incident?
剛來紐約時有些零零碎碎的事，
Well, there were some odds and ends
那是在我剛到紐約的時候。
when I first came to New York.
但在遇到 James 之後，我再也沒有偷過東西。
But then after I met James, I never stole anything.
直到……直到什麼時候？
Until... until when?
直到我的婚禮那天。
Until my wedding day.
我永遠忘不了那天 James 看起來有多英俊。
I'll never forget how handsome James looked that day.
我當時非常地愛他。
I was terribly in love with him.
但看起來，我的伴娘 Mildred Halliday 也是如此。
But so, it seems, was my matron of honor, Mildred Halliday.
她並非我親自選的，
She wasn't exactly my choice,
只是她的父親是那家銀行的董事會成員。
but her father was on the board of the bank.
在招待會上，James 突然消失了。
At the reception, James suddenly disappeared.
後來當我回想時，
When I came to think about it,
我好像也找不到 Mildred。
I couldn't seem to locate Mildred either.
我當時並不懷疑，真的，
I wasn't suspicious, really,
但我開始懷疑這件事也許並非不可能。
but I began to wonder if it wasn't just possible.
果然如此。
It was.
在這種情況下，
In situations like this,
我總會想出一些巧妙的話來說。
I always think of clever things to say.
好了，該切蛋糕了。
Well, time to cut the cake.
你好，Penelope。
Hello, Penelope.
Jimmy 和我剛纔在談婚禮的事。
Jimmy and I were just discussing weddings.
是的，我聽見了你們。
Yes, I heard you.
大家總是親新娘，
Well, everybody always kisses the bride,
但——沒人想到新郎。
but-but-but no one thinks of the groom.
除了你。
Except you.
嗯，這是我的慷慨本性。
Well, it's my generous nature.
哦，Jim，Jim，看看，你臉上全是口紅。
Oh, Jim, Jim, look. You're all over lipstick.
哦，別吃醋，親愛的。
Oh, don't be jealous, love.
Jimmy 和我認識很久了。
Jimmy and I have known each other for ages.
謝謝。
Ta.
我曾一度想背後捅她一刀，
I thought briefly about stabbing her in the back,
但我怕蛋糕刀不夠鋒利。
but I was afraid the cake knife wasn't sharp enough.
你想要解釋一下嗎？
Would you care for an explanation?
不用，你不必這樣做。
No, you don't have to.
感覺如何？
How was it?
我可以接受也可以不接受。
I could take it or leave it.
你把她的口紅都擦掉了嗎？
Have you got all of her lipstick off?
希望沒有。怎麼了？
No, I hope. Why?
那時候，沒人會懷疑 James 是個銀行家。
In those days, you'd never suspect James was a banker.
準備好了，大家，準備！他們來了！
Ready, everybody, ready! Here they come!
好啦，Penelope，讓我們看看你能不能擊中未來的新娘。
Alright, Penelope, let's see you hit a future bride.
我仍然記得 Mildred 仰望我的樣子。
I can still see Mildred looking up at me.
她戴着綠寶石的耳環和項鍊，
She was wearing her emerald earrings and necklace,
還有一副極爲高傲的表情。
plus a very superior expression.
到了拋新娘花束的時候了。
It was time to toss the wedding bouquet.
我決定讓 Mildred 抓到它。
I decided I'd let Mildred have it.
哦，Mildred。
Oh, Mildred.
哦，親愛的，真是太抱歉了。
Oh, darling, I'm terribly sorry.
哦，那太好了，親愛的。
Oh, that's good, darling.
謝謝。
Ta.
- 再見，我的愛。 - 再見。
- Goodbye, my love. - Goodbye.
而——親愛的，親愛的，
And-and-and, darling, darling,
請不要忘了從此過上幸福快樂的生活。
please don't forget to live happily ever after.
- 我會的，再見。再見。 - 再見，James。
- I will, bye. Bye. - Goodbye, James.
- 再見，Douglas。 - 再見！
- Goodbye, Douglas. - Bye!
我的，我的耳環。我的耳環！
My, my earrings. My earrings!
當我們十天後回家時，
And when we returned home ten days later,
項鍊和耳環仍然在盆栽棕櫚的罐子裏。
the necklace and earrings were still in the potted palm jar.
- 你從未歸還它們嗎？ - 沒有。我爲什麼要還？
- And you never returned them? - No. Why should 1?
我怎麼能幫你呢？
How am I going to help you?
對不起，Gregory。
I'm sorry, Gregory.
- 我會盡量做得更好。 - 好吧。
- I'll try to do better. - Alright.
現在，我要你在回答前仔細想一想
Now, I want you to think very carefully
再回答這個問題。
before you answer this.
每次你偷了東西之後，
Each time you stole something,
你記得事後你的感受嗎？
do you remember how you felt afterwards?
有罪感嗎？
Guilty?
難過嗎？
Upset?
沮喪。
Depressed.
不安。
Disturbed.
開心。
Cheerful.
你怎麼會感到開心？
How can you feel cheerful?
Gregory，這就是我來找你的原因。
Gregory, that's why I'm here.
想找出爲什麼偷東西會讓我感到開心。
To try to find out why stealing makes me cheerful.
你不可能。你不可能感到開心。
You couldn't. You couldn't possibly feel cheerful.
這也是我沒有的一個缺點。
Which is one fault that I do not have.
是盜竊癖，沒錯。
Kleptomania, yes.
但不等於不誠實。
Dishonesty, no.
你不是個竊盜癖患者。
You are not a kleptomaniac.
竊盜癖者是出於衝動偷竊，
A kleptomaniac steals out of compulsion,
而你是因爲享受而偷。
but you steal because you enjoy it.
你生我的氣。是的，我生氣。
You're angry with me. You bet I am.
我們最好現在就結束這次會面。
And we better end this session right here.
爲什麼？因爲我……
Why? Because I...
因爲我發現我無法……
Because I find I cannot...
我無法保持適當的超然態度。
I cannot maintain a proper attitude of detachment.
而且，你的時間也到了。
And besides, your time is up.
是的。
Yes.
Elcott 先生正在給 Elcott 太太打電話。
Mr. Elcott is calling Mrs. Elcott.
哦，我想知道會有什麼緊急事。
Oh, I wonder what could be so urgent.
可能和他妻子搶他銀行這事有關。
It may have something to do with his wife sticking up his bank.
是的，James？
Yes, James?
哦。
Oh.
他今晚不能回家吃飯。
He won't be home for dinner.
爲什麼，不是親愛的？
Why not, darling?
不。
No.
看在上帝的份上。
For heaven's sakes.
什麼？
What?
你有？
You have?
什麼時候？
When?
哦，James，我可以去嗎？
Oh, James, can I come?
哦，謝謝你，親愛的。
Oh, thank you, darling.
是的，是的，是的，我保證不會遲到。
Yes, yes, yes, I promise I won't be late.
Gregory，猜怎麼着？
Gregory, guess what?
他們有搶劫的影片，
They have movies of the robbery,
James 會讓我和警察一起看。
and James is gonna let me see them with the police.
我在鏡頭裏。多激動啊！
I'm on film. Isn't that exciting?
就像演員拍試鏡一樣。
It's just like an actress having a screen test.
只不過你如果演了這個角色，就得在監獄裏演。
Except that you get this part, you're gonna play it in jail.
Gregory，我得走了。
Gregory, I'd better run.
還有一千件事要做。拜拜。
I've got a thousand things to do first. Bye.
謝謝你，Gregory。我什麼時候再見你？
Thank you, Gregory. When do I see you again?
表現良好，差不多二十年以後。
With good behavior, in about 20 years.
明天，同一時間。同一時間。
Tomorrow, same time. Same time.
假如你還逍遙法外的話。
Assuming you're still at large.
Knoblock 醫生，我想是時候繼續我的分析了。
Dr. Knoblock, I think it's time we resume my analysis.
你看，我已經愛上了這個女竊賊……
You see, I've fallen in love with this bank robber...
- 哦，我能幫你嗎？ - 哦，是的，夫人。
- Oh, may I help you? - Oh, oui, madame.
我帶來一套西裝，想捐給你們的慈善機構。
I have here a suit to donate to your charity.
哦，謝謝你。
Oh, thank you.
呃，收據要寫給誰？
Uh, to whom shall we make out the receipt?
- 再見。 - 這可以免稅，你知道的。
- Bye. - It's tax deductible, you know.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
等一下！
Wait a minute!
太漂亮了。我就要了。
It's gorgeous. I'll take it.
- 你來晚了！ - 嘿！
- You are too late! - Say!
- 哦，求你了！ - 你在幹什麼？
- Oh, please! - What are you doing?
女士們！女士們！女士們！女士們！
Ladies! Ladies! Ladies! Ladies!
這麼大的騷動。爲了什麼？
Such a big commotion. Over what?
某件黃色的破布？
Some yellow rag?
這種顏色不適合你那病態的膚色。
The color's all wrong for your sallow complexion.
而黃？對你這年齡的女人來說更不合適。
And yellow? On a woman of your years?
你打算爲這件付多少錢，女士？
How much were you going to pay for this, lady?
嗯，呃，20美元。好像公平。
Well, uh, uh, $20. That seems fair.
- 21。 - 這是破損貨。看。
- 21. - It's damaged goods. Look.
那樣的話，不管多少錢我都不感興趣。
In that case, I'm not interested at any price.
那我也不感興趣了。
Then neither am I.
哦，親愛的。
Oh, dear.
這是 7 美元。
Here's $7.
比它值的還多。
More than it's worth.
不過我就是這麼個軟心腸的人。
But then I'm such a soft touch.
哦。
Oh.
Sadaba，我的生命之愛，
Sadaba, love of my life,
你知道我們這裏有什麼嗎？
do you know what we have here?
那不可能。
It couldn't be.
但它絕不會是別的東西。
But it couldn't be anything else.
沒人，沒人能像 Givenchy 那樣縫合。
Nobody, nobody does seams like Givenchy.
一件來自巴黎的原作，7 美元。
A Paris original for $7.
你太聰明瞭。
You're a genius.
愛上天使。
In love with an angel.
你那富有的天使。
Your rich angel.
在店裏我們能賣到 500 美元。
In the shop, we'll get $500 for this.
加上掛架，一共六件。
And a good hanger, six.
請幫助窮人。
Please help the poor.
請朋友們，敞開你們的心。
Please, friends, open your hearts.
主愛喜樂地施予者。
The lord loves a cheerful giver.
請朋友們，敞開你們的心。
Please, friends, open your hearts.
幫助他人。
Help others.
打擾一下，先生。
Pardon, monsieur.
施比受更爲有福，不是嗎？
It is more blessed to give than to take, no?
是的，我們被教導如此。
So we've been taught. Yes.
嗯，可惜不是相反的那樣。
Hm, too bad it is not the other way around.
是啊。
Yes.
謝謝，謝謝。
Thank you. Thank you.
嘿，等一下，我忘了我的...
Hey, wait a minute, I forgot my...
算了。
Never mind.
Cracker Jack?
我們馬上就看到嫌疑人的
We're coming up on our first good look
第一張清晰臉孔了。
at the suspect right here.
- 終於。 - 是時候了。
It's about time.
- 現在怎樣？ - 哦，是我太太。
- Now what? - Oh, it's my wife.
呃，親愛的，中士 Bixbee。
Uh, darling, lieutenant Bixbee.
- 你好嗎？ - 還有羅斯柴爾德中士。
- How do you do? - And sergeant Rothschild.
你好。
Hello.
我是不是錯過什麼了？
Am I, uh, missing anything?
從我站的地方看還沒丟什麼東西。
Not from where I'm standin'.
呃，中士，你既然在倒帶，
Uh, sergeant, as long as you're rewinding that
爲什麼不從頭開始給 Elcott 太太看？
why don't you start from the top for Mrs. Elcott?
哦，那真是太好了。
Oh, that's very kind.
- Cracker Jack？ - 謝謝。
- Cracker Jack? - Thank you.
謝謝。
Thank you.
你的鞋子？親愛的，你的鞋子在哪？
Your shoes? Where are your shoes, darling?
噢，真巧。我把鞋落在出租車裏了。
Oh, wouldn't you know it? I left them in the taxi.
上週是在電梯裏。
Last week, it was in the elevator.
我可以發出尋物通告。
I could send out an all-points bulletin.
我希望你在找我太太的鞋子比找我銀行被搶一案更有運氣。
I hope you have more luck with my wife's shoes
你的銀行，我的竊賊。記得嗎。
than you're having with my bank robbery.
哦，這太刺激了。
Your bank, my robber. Remember.
Oh, this is so exciting.
James，就是你。
James, that's you.
哦，James，你看起來真英俊。
Oh, James, you look so handsome.
什麼時候能看到那個女孩？
When do we get to see the girl?
現在。
Right now.
她在那兒了。
There she is.
讓開路！
Out of the way!
我看不到她！
I can't see her!
哦，也許還有更多。
Oh, maybe there's more.
- 轉過來！轉過來！ - 是的，轉過來！
- Turn around! Turn around! - Yes, turn around!
把膠片放慢。
Slow down the film.
哦，她不見了。
Oh, she's gone.
把那部分倒回去。
Run that part backwards.
哦，我喜歡那一幕。
Oh, I like that.
好了，就這些了。
Well, that's it.
嫌疑人，年輕的白人女性，
Suspect, young white female,
身高 5 英尺 3 英寸，紅髮，黃色套裝。
5'3", red hair, yellow suit.
我忘了什麼嗎？
Did I forget anything?
是的，從後面看時，
Yeah, when viewed from behind,
她的後襬非常吸引人地擺動。
she has a very attractive wiggle.
- 打擾一下，Elcott 太太。- 沒關係。
Excuse me, Mrs. Elcott. -not at all.
幫不上太大忙，是嗎？
Not much help, was it?
不。真遺憾。
No. What a shame.
別人臉都很清楚。
Everyone else's face was so clear.
你看起來真棒, James。
You were very good, James.
而 Serena 小姐簡直棒極了。
And miss Serena was just fabulous.
是的，考慮到她一直張着嘴。
Yeah, considering she kept her mouth open all the time.
嗯。
Mm.
順便說一句，你們的攝像機位置很有策略性。
Incidentally, your cameras are very strategically located.
我們可沒料到會拍到女洗手間。
We weren't expecting to photograph the ladies' washroom.
是的，Bixbee。
Yeah. Bixbee.
哦，很好。
Oh, very good.
我們破案的第一個突破。
Our first break in the case.
這麼快？我可能低估你了。
So soon? I may have underestimated you.
幹得好，警官。
Good work, officer.
我們在時代廣場設了路障。
We set up a roadblock in Times Square.
中尉，你真貼心。
Lieutenant, how dear of you.
哦，James，他真體貼，不是嗎？
Oh, James, wasn't that sweet of him?
可愛。
Adorable.
Bixbee 中尉？
Lieutenant Bixbee?
我已經給過了。
I already gave.
哦，我是 Higgins 少校。
Oh, I'm major Higgins.
我很忙。
I'm very busy.
聽聽，這哪是一箇中尉對
Well, that's a fine way for a lieutenant
少校該有的說話態度！
to talk to a major.
呃，呃，中尉，
Uh, uh, lieutenant,
我想請問這是真的還是假的。
I was wondering if you could tell me if this is real.
打擾一下。
Excuse me a minute.
少校，你從哪兒弄到這個的？
Major, where did you get this?
一位年輕女士在大約五點鐘把它放進我的鼓裏。
A young lady put it in my tambourine about 5 o'clock.
你能描述她嗎？
Could you describe her?
她的衣着，她的膚色？
Her clothes, her coloring?
身高，身材如何？
Her height, her figure?
呃，Elcott 太太，你能站起來嗎？
Uh, Mrs. Elcott, would you stand up, please?
哦，當然。
Oh, of course.
是的，是的，她大約和這位小姐一樣高。
Yes, yes, she was just about this young lady's height.
而且身材也差不多。
And figure.
只是……
Only...
只是什麼？
Only what?
只是金髮。
Only with blond hair.
還有別的嗎？有的。
Anything else? Yes.
她帶着法國口音說話而且……
She spoke with a French accent and...
她臉頰上有一粒痣。
She had a mole on her cheek.
打擾一下，就在這裏。
Excuse me. Right here.
謝謝。
Thank you.
你還記得她說了什麼嗎？
Can you remember anything she said?
是的，我相信她的原話是
Yes, I believe her exact words were
“施比受更有福，不是嗎？”
"it is more blessed to give than to take, no?"
哦，我們需要像她這樣的人。
Oh, we need workers like her.
那麼樂於助人，那麼，呃……
So willing, so, uh...
快樂？快樂。
Cheerful? Cheerful.
是的，是的，那正是這個詞。快樂。
Yes, yes, that's the exact word. Cheerful.
是的，她看起來是個可愛的人。
Yeah, she seemed such a sweet person.
錢不是很好嗎？
Isn't the money good?
嗯，對你來說不行，少校。
Well, not for you, major.
這張鈔票是今天下午被盜的
This bill was stolen this afternoon
從 Elcott 先生的銀行。
from Mr. Elcott's bank.
哦，那真讓我很抱歉。
Well, I'm sorry about that.
但我只是抱有一線希望。
But I was just hoping.
哦，好吧。
Oh, well.
少校，等等！
Major, wait!
Bixbee 中尉，這不公平。
Lieutenant Bixbee, this is unfair.
法律不必公平。這就是法律。
It doesn't have to be fair. It's the law.
什麼法律？我從未聽說過這種法律。
What law? I never heard of any such law.
我的意思是，他爲什麼不能留着它？
I mean, why can't he keep it?
畢竟，他並沒有偷它。有人把它給了他。
After all, he didn't steal it. Somebody gave it to him.
那不是她有權贈與的，親愛的。
It wasn't hers to give, darling.
但他需要它。
But he needs it.
你就什麼都不能做嗎？
Isn't there anything you can do?
恐怕不行。
I'm afraid not.
那好，James，你來做點什麼吧。
Well, then, James, you do something.
呃，比如什麼？
Uh, like what?
給 Higgins 少校開一張支票。
Write major Higgins a check.
- 爲了什麼，親愛的？ - 爲一千美元。
- For what, darling? - For $1000.
那就是你要從他那裏拿走的。
That's what you're taking from him.
- 拿走？ - 當然了。
- Taking? - Well, of course.
而且，你會打平賬。
And besides, you'll be breaking even.
親愛的，你這是怎麼想出來的？
How do-how do you figure that out, darling?
因爲 Higgins 少校把你的 1000 美元還給了你，
Well, major Higgins gave you back your $1000.
你把他的 1000 美元還給他。很簡單。
You give him back his $1000. Simple.
我聽到的是嗎？真不敢相信。
Am I hearing right? I can't believe this.
James！
James!
如果你不給 Higgins 少校開支票，
If you don't give major Higgins a check,
我就再也不跟你說話了。
I'll never speak to you again.
哦，拜託，諸位，拜託。
Oh, please, folks, please.
我們的職責是減輕別人的煩惱，不是製造煩惱。
We're meant to ease people's troubles, not to cause them.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
拜託，James。
Please, James.
哦，謝謝你，親愛的。
Oh, thank you, darling.
五百？
Five hundred?
一千。
A thousand.
等着吧，這件事傳到
Wait till word of this reaches
紅十字會、基督教青年會和哈達薩會去。
Red Cross, YMCA and Hadassah.
你知道嗎？
And do you know what?
James 仍然不明白他在這筆交易中是打平了。
James still doesn't understand that he broke even on the deal.
也許他只是固執。
Maybe he was just being stubborn.
不，他只是糊塗。
No, he's just confused.
對一個銀行家來說，這很奇怪。
For a banker, I think that's pretty strange.
這些牛奶都對你有好處嗎？
Is all this milk good for you?
不是給我的，是給我的潰瘍的。
It's not for me, it's for my ulcer.
你知道，Bixbee 中尉非常好
You know, lieutenant Bixbee was so nice
幫我找回我的鞋子。
about getting back my shoes.
你猜我爲什麼拿了它們？
Why do you suppose I took this?
Gregory。
Gregory.
噎着了嗎？
Go down the wrong pipe?
Penelope。
Penelope.
Penelope，你有沒有想過
Penelope, did you, did you ever think
去看另一位精神科醫生？
of going to another psychiatrist?
不，那樣不忠誠。
No, that would be disloyal.
我一點也幫不了你。
I'm not helping you at all.
當然你幫了。
Of course you are.
Gregory，對不起。我會把錢包寄回去。
Gregory, I'm sorry. I'll send the wallet back.
不止是這個。
It's not only this.
哦，別因爲我搶了家銀行就氣餒。
Oh, don't be discouraged just because I stuck up a bank.
是你丈夫的銀行。
Your husband's bank.
是的，James 的銀行。
Yeah, James' bank.
爲什麼是他那家銀行？爲什麼不是別人的？
Why his bank? Why not somebody else's bank?
你爲什麼用左手寫字？
Why are you writing left-handed?
我是事後幫助掩護的人。
I'm being an accessory after the fact.
你介意替我舔一下這個嗎？
Would you mind licking this for me?
我太乾了。
I'm too dry.
你當初怎麼會嫁給那樣的男人？
Whatever made you marry a man like that in the first place?
哦，James 起初並不是那種男人。
Oh, James wasn't a man like that in the first place.
哦，不。
Oh, no.
我第一次遇到 James 是在格林威治村的一個酒窖裏
The first time I met James was at a Greenwich village cellar
叫做 Plush Pig。
known as the plush pig.
我在那裏工作了幾個月。
I'd been working there a couple of months.
那是我在紐約的第一份正經工作。
It was my first real job in New York.
♪ 我是個知道自己是誰的人 ♪
♪ I'm someone who knows who I am ♪
♪ 但當你遠離我時 ♪
♪ but when you are far away ♪
♪ 我的世界變得陰霾 ♪
♪ my world is clouded ♪
♪ 太陽也變得灰暗 ♪
♪ the sun is gray ♪
♪ 你能讓我觸及天空 ♪
♪ you can make me touch the sky ♪
♪ 給我翅膀幫助我飛翔 ♪
♪ give me wings and help me fly ♪
♪ 但沒有你無論晝夜 ♪
♪ but without you night and day ♪
♪ 我的世界都籠罩着陰霾 ♪
♪ my world is clouded ♪
♪ 太陽也變得灰暗 ♪
♪ the sun is gray ♪
♪ 你掛起月亮 ♪
♪ you hang the moon ♪
♪ 在天空中撒滿星辰 ♪
♪ scatter stars throughout the sky ♪
♪ 我內心所有的美好 ♪
♪ all of the good things within me ♪
♪ 都必須透過你的眼來見證 ♪
♪ must first be seen through your eye ♪
♪ 只有一件事是錯的 ♪
♪ there is only one thing wrong ♪
♪ 太陽是灰色的 ♪
♪ the sun is gray ♪
魔鬼的小提琴在說話。
The devil's fiddle speaks.
嗨。
Hi.
- 嗯。Penelope Gordon 小姐？ - 嗯哼。
- Huh. Miss Penelope Gordon? - Mm-hm.
如果你坐下，就不用彎着腰了。
If you sit down, you won't have to scrunch over.
我可以請你喝一杯，但只有水。
I'd offer you a drink, but it's only water.
你介意我把眼睛取出來嗎？
Would you excuse me while I take out my eyes?
我是 James Elcott，市聯邦銀行。
I'm James Elcott, city federal bank.
嗯，隱形眼鏡。
Hm, contacts.
哦，現在我能看得更清楚你了。
Oh, now I can see you much better.
好吧，我從沒和銀行握過手。
Well, I never shook hands with a bank before.
Penelope Gordon 小姐，我怎麼沒收到你的來信？
How is it I haven't heard from you, miss Gordon?
嗯，可能是因爲我們剛認識不久。
Well, it's probably because we've only just met.
但在過去兩個月我給你寫了九封信。
But I've written you nine times in the last two months.
哦，你真喜歡民謠，是嗎？
Oh, you really love folk songs, do you?
並不完全是。不，這事是公務。
Not exactly. No, this is business.
市聯邦接受了一個小遺產的受託管理
City federal has accepted trusteeship of a modest estate
是你母親的表親留給你的。
left to you by your mother's cousin.
你確定是對的 Penelope Gordon 嗎？
Are you sure you've got the right Penelope Gordon?
絕對。
Absolutely.
遺產的收入不會很多，
The income from the estate won't be much,
但有些文件需要簽字。
but there are papers to sign.
你真的從未收到過我的任何信嗎？
You're certain you never received any of my letters?
啊，我知道怎麼回事了。
Ah, I know what happened.
你看，我從不打開我的郵件。
You see, I never open my mail.
哦，誰替你打開？
Oh, who does it for you?
- 沒有人。 - 那郵件都去哪兒了？
- Nobody. - What happens to it?
通常我把它塞進抽屜裏某處，
Well, usually, I stick it away in a drawer someplace
然後總是忘了或丟了。
and then I always forget it or it gets lost.
你不會因此失去很多朋友嗎？
Don't you lose a lot of friends that way?
哦，不，正好相反。
Oh, no, just the opposite.
你看，如果你寫信給我而我回信，
You see, if you write me a letter and I answer it,
那你就得回我信。
then you have to answer mine.
然後我回答你的第二封，你得寫第三封
Then I answer your second letter and you have to write me a third
並回答我的第二封。
and answer to my second.
然後我得寫第三封，
And then I have to write you a third
你得寄第四封。
and you have to send me a fourth.
很快，我們忙着互相寫信，
And pretty soon, we're so busy writing letters to each other
就沒時間做朋友了。
we haven't got time to be friends.
是嗎？
Isn't that true?
嗯，我從沒這麼想過，嗯。
Uh, I-i-I never, I never thought of it like that, hm.
無論如何，我可以回家再找找你的信。
Well, anyway, I-I could still look for your letters at home.
那有幫助嗎？
Would that help?
嗯，我們應該討論這些，是的。
Well, we ought to discuss them, yes.
哦，親愛的。
Oh, dear.
怎麼了？
What is it?
我把隱形眼鏡掉了。我總是弄丟它們。
I've dropped my contact lens. I'm always losing them.
哦，別把褲子弄髒。
Oh, oh, don't get your pants dirty.
哦，沒事的。
Oh, that's alright.
你、嗯，你覺得我們可以、呃，
Do you, um, do you think we could, uh,
明天找個時間見面嗎？
get together sometime tomorrow?
哦，當然，吃個晚飯怎麼樣？
Oh, sure, how about dinner?
我——我要請些朋友來。
I-I'm gonna have some friends in.
呃，那太好了。
Uh, that's wonderful.
哦，這些隱形眼鏡，真小。
Oh, these contacts, they're so tiny.
我們怎麼可能找到它們呢。
We're never going to find them.
那，有關係嗎？
Well, does it matter?
你自己不是說過不用它們看得更清楚嗎。
You said yourself, you can see better without them.
哦，清楚多了。
Oh, much better.
我想以前和我約會的那位驗光師
I think this optometrist I was dating
給了我錯的處方。
gave me the wrong prescription.
我能問你件事嗎？
May I ask something?
你爲什麼戴它們？
Why do you wear them?
嗯，他說它們能讓我的眼睛顯得有神采。
Well, he said they make my eyes look luminous.
我覺得我的眼睛本來就很有神采了。
I think they're luminous already.
而且也挺漂亮的。
And quite beautiful.
哦，那好，那麼我就不用戴隱形眼鏡了，是嗎？
Oh, well, then I don't need to wear the contacts, do I?
我很高興你來看我。
I'm glad you came to see me.
我也是。
So am I.
我很期待明晚。
I'm looking forward to tomorrow night.
我也是。
So am I.
現在我想起來了，可以請你站起來嗎？
And now I'd like to get up, please.
什麼？
Pardon?
你跪在我的頭髮上了。
You're kneeling on my hair.
- 哦，我太... - 哦，小心那個...
- Oh, I'm terribly... - Oh, watch out for the...
菸斗。
Pipe.
哦，天哪。哦。
Oh, dear. Oh.
真是非常抱歉。
I'm terribly sorry.
你還好嗎？
A-are you alright?
沒事，完全沒事。
It's alright. Quite alright.
沒什麼好擔心的。
There's nothing to concern yourself about.
哎呀。
Oh, dear.
哦，你找到了我的隱形眼鏡。
Oh, you found my contact lens.
嗯？
Yeah?
Penelope Gordon 小姐？
Miss Penelope Gordon?
這是銀行嗎？
Is this the bank?
是的。我上去嗎？
Yes. Shall I come up?
不用了，你可以在樓下等。
No, but you're welcome down here.
明白了。
Got it.
希望我在村子裏穿得不過分隆重。
I hope I'm not overdressed for the village.
不會的，我不會這麼說。
No, I wouldn't say so.
進來，認識大家吧。
Come on in and meet everybody.
大家，這是 James Elcott。
Everybody, meet James Elcott.
你這打扮不像個銀行家。
You're dressed funny for a banker.
- 我可以回家換衣服。 - 哦，不，我覺得很可愛。
- I could go home and change. - Oh, no, I think it's sweet.
你爲我們打扮，我們也爲你打扮。
You dressed for us and we dressed for you.
Penelope，幫忙。
Penelope, help.
你知道這種場合會讓我緊張。
You know these things make me nervous.
別慌，Sebastian。救援馬上到。
Don't panic, Sebastian. Help is on the way.
- 我就一會兒。 - 我會記着你的。
- I'll just be a sec. - I'm going to hold you to that.
我瞭解你。
I know you.
你在市聯邦銀行存錢嗎？
Do you bank at city federal?
我把錢塞在牀墊裏。
I bank in my mattress.
那也不錯。
Well, that's nice too.
昨晚在 Plush Pig，
Last night at plush pig,
你在我重要的那段演出時走了。
you walked out on my big number.
是個無心的冒犯。
An unintentional slight.
話說得輕巧。現在想聽嗎？
Talk's cheap. Wanna hear it now?
- 就在這兒，沒有你的樂隊？ - 我會假唱給你聽。
- Right here without your band? - I'll fake it for you.
我要去把我的朋友從 Boom Boom 那兒救出來。
I've got to rescue my friend from boom boom.
我要去救那位商人。
I shall rescue the businessman.
請把我的禮物講完。
Please finish my present.
畢竟這是你的生日。
Well, it's your birthday.
來段《Greensleeves》快版如何？
How about a fast arrangement of "Greensleeves?"
等一下，Boom Boom。那個人是我的。
Just a minute, boom boom. He's mine.
哦，拜託，Sebastian。
Oh, come on, Sebastian.
我敢說你在哪兒都能適應。
I bet you fit in any place.
- 我喜歡你的朋友。 - 他們隨租約一塊來的。
- I like your friends. - They came with the lease.
那也隨租約帶來的嗎？
Did that come with the lease too?
不是。我曾和一個焊工約會過。
No. I used to date this welder.
他一定是個糟糕的司機。
He must have been an awful driver.
不，我還有一個男朋友，開廢品場的。
No, I had this other boyfriend who owns a junkyard.
你男朋友真多，不是嗎？
You got a lot of boyfriends, haven't you?
嗯。你是我的第一個銀行家。
Hm. You're my first banker.
爲什麼要到處逛？
Why all this shopping around?
如果你不試所有東西，
Well, if you don't try everything
怎麼知道自己真正喜歡什麼？
how are you gonna find out what you really like?
孩童之言真是金玉良言。
Out of the mouths of babes.
又來？
Again?
大家都去哪兒了？
Where did everybody go?
他們都在這兒。
They're all here.
三週後，我們結婚了。
Three weeks later, we got married.
匆匆忙忙，好像不結婚會死掉似的。
All in a rush. Like if we didn't, we'd die.
如果你老公還是那個
And if your husband was still the same
浪漫格林威治村 James，
romantic Greenwich village James,
你現在還會去偷東西嗎？
would you be stealing now?
哦，James 沒有時間談浪漫了。
Oh, James hasn't got time for romance.
他太忙於銀行工作。
He's too busy banking.
所以你還偷嗎？
So you steal?
你對這事過於冷靜了。
You're much too calm about it.
我爲什麼不能冷靜？
Well, why shouldn't I be calm?
畢竟，沒有什麼能把我和搶劫聯繫起來。
After all, there's nothing to connect me with the robbery.
除了那件黃色套裝。
Except the yellow suit.
你知道警察在全城搜尋它嗎。
You realize the police are combing the city for it.
嗯，我有看到報道。
Mm, so I've read.
我已經處理掉了。
I took care of it.
你把它燒了嗎？
You burned it?
沒有，我把它捐給了舊貨店。
No, I gave it away to a thrift shop.
舊貨店？
Thrift shop?
你知道你這樣做有多冒險嗎？
Do you realize the chance you're taking?
我不知道。
I don't know.
也許我會去把它買回來。
Maybe I'll go buy it back.
買回來？不，不行！
Buy it? No, no!
Penny，看。
Penny, look.
你這是想被抓嗎，嗯？
Are you trying to get caught, mm?
你根本就不該去那兒。
You never should have gone there in the first place.
那我還能怎麼辦？把它扔掉？
Well, what else could I do? Throw it away?
那樣會安全得多。
It would have been a lot safer.
Gregory，那是件 Givenchy 套裝。
Gregory, it was a Givenchy suit.
然後呢？
So?
你不能把 Givenchy 扔進下水道。
Well, you can't just throw a Givenchy down a manhole.
那簡直是褻瀆。
It's sacrilege.
再說，James 爲那套衣服付了1100美元，
And besides, James paid $1100 for that suit
我可不想看到他浪費錢。
and I wouldn't like to see him waste his money.
嗨。Bixbee 中尉。羅斯柴爾德中士。
Hi. Lieutenant Bixbee. Sergeant Rothschild.
真是個意外的驚喜。
What a nice surprise.
Elcott 太太，你經常來這兒買嗎？
Mrs. Elcott, do you shop here?
是的，我常來。他們有許多有趣的東西。
Yes, I often drop by. They have fascinating things.
他們昨天確實有。那兒有那件黃色套裝。
They did yesterday. They had the yellow suit.
並非完全如此。
Not really.
他們怎麼得到的？
How did they get it?
嗯，他們得到它的方式和
Well, they got it the same way
Higgins 少校弄到那張1000美元鈔票的方式一樣。
that major Higgins got his $1000 bill.
是個金髮的女孩捐的，她帶着裝出來的法國口音。
It was donated by a blond girl with a phony French accent.
- 然後我們追查到了這裏。 - 真聰明啊你們。
- And we traced it here. - Well, how clever of you.
也沒那麼聰明。
Well, not so clever.
後面那位女士在報上看到後打電話給我們。
The lady back there read about it in the paper and called us.
但我們還夠聰明，接了電話。
But we were clever enough to pick up the phone.
好，那就這樣。你們找到了。
Well, that's that. You've got it.
還沒呢。有人買走了。只付了七塊錢。
Not yet. Somebody bought it. Paid seven bucks.
- 七塊？那…… - 怎麼了？太便宜嗎？
- Seven bucks? But that... - What? Too cheap?
這也說不準。
Well, that's hard to say.
我得先看看。
I'd have to see it first.
那你爲何不和我們一塊去拿呢？
Well, why don't you come along while we pick it up?
我能坐警車嗎？
Do I get to ride in a police car?
可以，有警笛，還有一切配備。
Yeah, with a siren and everything.
羅斯柴爾德中士總是這麼開車嗎？
Does sergeant Rothschild always drive like that?
他只是稍微賣弄一下而已。
He was just showin' off a little.
這是我第一次有機會參加警察突襲。
This is the first police raid I've ever been invited to.
你們要把門撞開嗎？
Are you gonna break down the door?
那種做法隨禁酒令時代一起過去了。
Well, you see, that went out with prohibition.
現在我們有了全新的形象。
Now we have a whole new image.
既時髦又有禮貌。
It's very suave and very couth.
所以進去後，你就跟着我做就行了。
So when we get inside, you just take your cue from me.
明白，長官。
Right, chief.
那是中尉，Elcott 太太。
That's lieutenant, Mrs. Elcott.
那是 Penelope，中尉。
That's Penelope, lieutenant.
Horatio。我的父親很愛讀書。
Horatio. My father read a lot.
嗯。嗯。
Mm. Mm.
哦，親愛的。
Oh, cherie.
這纔是我認爲的經典醃牛肉三明治。
Now that's what I call a vintage pastrami.
嗯哼。嗯。
Mm-hm. Mm.
嗯。
Mm.
美味的蒔蘿醃黃瓜...
Delish dill pickle...
沒什麼好挑剔的。
Is nothing to throw rocks at.
我感覺有點胃灼熱要起來了。
I feel a slight heartburn building up.
快，我的天使，奶油汽水。
Quickly, my angel, the cream soda.
啊，午安，女士們先生們。
Ah, good afternoon, lady and gentleman.
歡迎來到Princess Sadaba的沙龍。
Welcome to the salon of Princess Sadaba.
這家精品店非常時髦。
The boutique très chic.
- 你好。 - 啊，這國產香檳。
- Salut. - Ah, this domestic champagne.
啊，Princess Sadaba能爲您做些什麼？
Ah, and what can Princess Sadaba do for you?
別告訴我，我知道。
Don't tell me, I know.
身材如此迷人，您顯然
With such a lovely figure, you have obviously
是來爲Sadaba的某件華麗晚禮服而來。
come for one of Sadaba's divine evening gowns.
哦，不，是套裝。或者說是一套套裝。
Oh, no, a suit. Or a suit.
你看，Sadaba 是多麼懂得。
You see how Sadaba knows.
我想要亮色的，我要去波託菲諾。
I'd like something bright. I'm going to Portofino.
波託菲諾！哦，真是命中註定。
Portofino! Oh, it is like fate.
快，把我們爲她留着的那件拿出來。
Quick, the number we have been saving for her.
- Sadaba 女士是通靈的。 - 真的嗎？
- Madame Sadaba is psychic. - Really?
三週前她特意從巴黎訂了這套衣服。
Three weeks ago, she sends all the way to Paris for this suit.
爲什麼？因爲她知道你會需要它去波多黎各。
Why? Because she knows you will be needing it for p-Puerto Rico.
Ducky，親愛的，把那個拿出來。
Ducky, darling, bring out the you-know-what.
馬上，陛下。
Right away, majesty.
瞧！
Et voilà
就是它。
here we are.
剛從巴黎下飛機的貨。
Hot off the plane from Paris.
我相信你。它還熱乎着呢。
I believe you. It's still warm.
試穿吧。
Try it on.
- 爲什麼？ - 爲什麼不呢？
- Why? - Why not?
你穿黃色會很好看。
You'd look good in yellow.
Sadaba 不僅通靈，還是個天才。
Sadaba is not only psychic, she's a genius.
看吧，合身得像是爲她量身定做的一樣。
Look, see how it fits. Like it was made for her.
我也有同感。
That's just what I was thinking.
我也是。簡直太美了。
So was I. It's absolutely divine.
就是你了。
It's just you.
是的，就是你。
Yeah. Yeah, it's just you.
謝謝。我真想要它。
Thank you. I'd love to have it.
不過再想想，也許 Sadaba 要留着這件給自己。
On second thought, maybe Sadaba keeps this creation for herself.
- 哦。- 哦，拜託，拿下來。
- Oh. - Oh, please take it off.
Sadaba 捨不得把它給出去。
Sadaba cannot bear to part with it.
多少錢？
How much?
爲了你，Sadaba 幾乎不賣，
Oh, for you, Sadaba lets it go for practically nothing.
六百美元。
Six hundred dollars.
說句公道話，Princess，你真有膽量。
I'll say this for you, Princess, you got a lot of guts.
那是和皇室說話的方式嗎？
Is that the way to talk to royalty?
Ducky，親愛的，上樓把盒子拿來。
Ducky, darling, go upstairs and get the box.
Ducky 會殺了我，但爲了讓你那位小太太高興，
Ducky will kill me, but to make your little wife happy,
這件 Givenchy 給你，價錢 595。
the Givenchy is yours for 595.
那位女士可不是我的妻子。
The lady is not my wife.
Sadaba 絕不會透露半句。
Sadaba will never breathe a word.
Sadaba 想怎麼說就怎麼說。
Sadaba can breathe all she wants.
我是紐約警察中尉 Bixbee。
I'm lieutenant Bixbee, New York police.
Ducky？
Ducky?
警察來了。
The cops.
呃，我們可沒做什麼違法的事。
Uh, we didn't do nothing illegal.
高價收費並不違法。
There's no law against overcharge.
放輕鬆，陛下。
Just relax, your majesty.
沒有人在指控任何人。
Nobody is accusing anybody of anything.
那件套裝是銀行搶劫案的物證。
The suit is evidence in a bank robbery.
報紙上都有報道。
It was in all the papers.
《基督教科學箴言報》上倒沒提到。
It was no mention of it in the Christian science monitor.
它在這裏。
Here it is.
穿在你身上會很好看。
It'll look lovely on you.
不，Elcott 太太，我們要把它帶走。
No, Mrs. Elcott, we're taking it.
- 哦？ - 把它包起來，Princess。
- Oh? - Wrap it up, Princess.
給你。大手大腳的花錢者。
Here. Big spender.
七塊錢就白花了。
Seven bucks down the drain.
別緊張。梅里爾·林奇請客。
Relax. Compliments of Merrill lynch.
淨賺三美元。
A whole $3 profit.
非常抱歉。你們的店真漂亮。
I'm terribly sorry. You do have a lovely shop.
有空我想再來。
I'd like to come back when I have more time.
嗯，很榮幸，很榮幸。
Um, pleasure, pleasure.
再見。
Bye.
那個名字，那張臉。
That name, that face.
我以前見過她，但在哪兒呢？
I have seen her before, but where?
在哪兒？在哪兒？
Where? Where?
Ducky，親愛的，我想我們應該馬上去翻閱
Ducky, precious, I think we go immediately browsing
公共圖書館的《Vogue》舊刊。
through the back issues of vogue
快去。
at the public library. Come on.
那女人竟然敢開那種價，真有膽量，不是嗎？
The dame's got a lot of nerve charging those figures, right?
其實，600美元也不是離譜得太遠。
Well, actually, $600 isn't too far out of line.
二手套裝嗎？
For a secondhand suit?
一套二手的 Givenchy 套裝。
A secondhand Givenchy suit.
我不記得 Sadaba 提過 Givenchy 的禮服。
I don't recall Sadaba mentioning a Givenchy suit.
至少在你在場的時候沒聽她提。
At least not while you were there.
- 她沒說？ - 沒有！
- She didn't? -No!
那我又是怎麼知道的呢？
Well, then how did I know?
哦，她確實說過巴黎。
Oh, she did say Paris.
我大概自己聯想起來的。
I must have put two and two together.
是啊。
Yeah.
對，可能就是這樣。
Yeah, that's probably it.
很好。
Very nice.
你知道，我說實話
You know, I was saying that in my line of work
在我這行裏，你不會常來這種地方。
you don't get a chance to spend much time in a joint like this.
我覺得這是
You know, I think this is probably
我在紐約最喜歡的地方之一。
my most favorite place in New York.
比你老公的銀行都好，Mrs. Elcott？
Better than your husband's bank, Mrs. Elcott?
怎麼我從 Penelope 又降格爲 Mrs. Elcott 了？
How did I get demoted from Penelope back to Mrs. Elcott?
好了。Penelope。
Alright. Penelope.
Penelope，你知道嗎...
Penelope, do you know...
大多數時候我挺喜歡我的工作。
Most of the time I like my job?
- 那是什麼？ - 那個？泡泡糖。
- What's that? - That? It's bubblegum.
- 我可以來一點嗎？ - 好，自己拿吧。
- May I have some? - Yeah, help yourself.
誰是 Ron Swoboda？
Who's Ron Swoboda?
我只是嚼嚼口香糖。
I just chew the gum.
你知道，關於犯罪有件有趣的事。
You know, it's a funny thing about crime.
但通常是無辜的嫌疑人
But it's the innocent suspect
看起來最像罪犯。
that usually looks the most guilty.
因爲他沒什麼可藏的。
That's because he's got nothing to hide.
放下了戒備。
Keeps his guard down.
而有罪的人則不停思考。
But the guilty ones, they're always thinking.
他們在注意自己的舉止、聲音、表情。
They're watching themselves pretty good.
最終正是他們的圓滑出賣了他們。
How will they sound and how will that look?
最終，正是他們那種圓滑把他們困住。
And in the end, it's their very smoothness that traps them.
真有意思。
It's fascinating.
你是怎麼做到的？
How do you do that?
你小時候是怎樣的？
Now what kind of a childhood did you have?
就是那種戴着牙套的。
The kind with braces on your teeth.
把口香糖攤平，把舌頭塞進去，
Spread the gum flat, poke your tongue into it
把口袋鼓滿空氣。
and fill the pocket with air.
- 我做到了！ - 初學者走運。
- I did it! - Beginner's luck.
Penelope，我是我所認識的最棒的警察……
Penelope, I am the best damn cop I know...
而這就是我的麻煩。
And that's my trouble.
我太過能幹，這反而成了我的問題。
I'm too damn good for my own damn good.
我覺得你很棒。
I think you're very good.
那位女銀行劫匪很快就會發現這點。
That's what that lady bank robber's about to find out.
你知道的，可憐的孩子沒機會了。
You know, that poor kid doesn't have a chance.
- 嗯。 - 自以爲是。
- Mm. -overconfident.
你看，我來自的那個街區裏，
You see, in the neighborhood that I come from
孩子只有三條出路。
a kid had three chances.
可以當混混，可以當警察，
He could be a hood, he could be a cop,
也可以當神父。
he could be a priest.
我太笨，沒法去偷東西，而且我們又不是天主教徒。
Well, I was too clumsy to steal and we weren't catholic.
要是我有個像樣的街區也許會不一樣。
Maybe if I'd had a neighborhood.
Penelope。怎麼了？
Penelope. What?
你經常去你丈夫的銀行嗎？
Did you spend a lot of time in your husband's bank?
不，能不去我就不去。怎麼了？
No, I hardly ever go there if I can help it. Why?
放影片的時候，
When we ran the film
你竟然能那樣立刻說出出納的名字。
you knew the teller's name just like that.
哦，當然我知道她的名字。
Well, of course I knew her name.
它就在櫃檯上的牌子上。
It was on a plaque on the counter.
你沒看到嗎？
Didn't you see it?
唔，我看來並不像
Well, I guess I'm not as good at my job
我以爲的那麼稱職，我沒注意到。
as I thought I was. I missed it.
哦。
Oh.
哦，親愛的。
Oh, dear.
怎麼了？
What's the matter?
我本來十分鐘前該去見 James 的。
I was supposed to meet James ten minutes ago.
那我能留住 Ron Swoboda 嗎？
Do I get to keep Ron Swoboda?
喂，Horatio，看這個。
Hey, Horatio, watch.
不錯吧，嗯？
Not bad, hm?
太棒了。
Terrific.
後來 James 在銀行開始升職。
Then James began to get promoted at the bank.
第三副總裁，第二副總裁，
Third vice president, second vice president,
第一副總裁。
first vice president.
終於，我們要說到你問題的關鍵了！
At last, we're getting to the crux of your problem!
你看不到嗎？
Don't you see it?
你覺得在你丈夫的生活中被排除在外，
You feel left out of your husband's life
於是你通過補償他對你的冷淡來彌補。
so you compensate for his lack of attention.
是嗎？
I do?
絕望之下，我開始培養一些愛好。
In desperation, I began taking up hobbies.
首先，是和 James 一起的愛好。
First, hobbies with James.
James！James！
James! James!
事情仍然很不確定。
Things were still pretty much up in the air.
於是我接着嘗試爲 James 而做的愛好。
So I next tried hobbies for James.
James！James！看看我們贏了什麼！
James! James! Look what we won!
乖孩子。
Good girl.
好男孩。
Good boy.
好吧，至少他先拍了我一下。
Well, at least he patted me first.
什麼辦法都沒用。
Nothing worked.
有趣的是。
It's funny.
只有一種愛好似乎能讓我高興起來。
There's only one hobby that seemed to cheer me up.
入室盜竊。
Burglary.
不是入室盜竊。那是強行進入。
Not burglary. That's forcible entry.
你犯的只是普通盜竊。
All you committed was simple larceny.
拜託，Gregory，我寧願把它當成入室盜竊來看。
Please, Gregory, I'd rather think of it as burglary.
那樣更刺激。
It's more exciting.
Penelope，你入室行竊的受害者有多少？
Penelope, how many victims did you burglarize?
你挑誰來下手的？
And whom did you choose to burgle?
呃，偷——偷竊。呃，Rob。
Uh, bur-burglarize. Uh, Rob.
我不知道。就是些人。
I don't know. Just people.
是的，人。
Yes, people. People who are your husband's
就是你丈夫的生意夥伴，對吧？
business associates, huh?
是的。
Yes.
不知爲什麼，我就是討厭他們。
For some reason, I just hated them.
無論我和 James 去哪兒，
No matter where James and I went
都甩不開金融界的那些事。
there was no getting away from the world of finance.
“總統關於稅收的聲明
"The president's statement on taxes
給市場帶來了拋售壓力。”
brought selling pressure into the market.
儘管他確實重申了那點……
And though he did reiterate that...
哦，我們去遊個泳吧。
Oh, let's go for a little swim.
呃，好吧……你不覺得現在有點晚了嗎？
Eh, well... don't you think it's late, isn't it?
哦，拜託。
Oh, come on.
在紐波特，是 Johanna Keller，
At Newport, it was Johanna Keller,
她是銀行最大的儲戶之一。
one of the bank's biggest depositors.
- 我最後吃的那根熱狗…… - 哦，拜託。
- The last hot dog I ate... - Oh, come on.
哦，求你了，小姐……
Oh, please, miss...
從那以後，我們就不怎麼見到 Keller 小姐了。
After that, we didn't see so much of miss Keller.
即便我們去跳舞，比如街區那晚，
Even when we'd go dancing, like the night at the block,
遲早，James 的銀行界朋友們
sooner or later, James' banking friends
會破壞我們的樂趣。
would manage to spoil our fun.
哦，遲早我得和他們談生意了。
Oh, sooner or later, I'm going to have to talk business with them.
我不明白爲什麼。
I don't see why.
畢竟，你又不是在銀行裏和他們跳舞，對吧？
After all, you don't dance with them at the bank, do you?
親愛的，我愛你。
I love you, darling.
我很慶幸不必和你談生意。
I'm glad I don't have to do business with you.
真不公平，你們倆。
Not fair, you two.
哦，那是“la Bostella”。
Oh, it's "la Bostella."
你就不能死嗎？
Couldn't you just die?
音樂一停，我們就都倒下。
When the music stops, we all fall down.
我就得收拾他一下。
I just had to fix him.
不錯。
Not bad.
鑽石王冠，三枚胸針，
Diamond tiara, three brooches,
九條手鐲和一條掛式項鍊。
nine bracelets and a lavaliere.
哦，我最精彩的一次是我拿走了……
Oh, and my best caper was when I took...
Penny，別說了。別說了。
Penny, just stop. Just stop.
但那還遠遠不止這些。
我可以講好幾個小時。
But there's lots more. I could go on for hours.
也許你可以，但我可做不到。
Maybe you could, but I couldn't.
Gregory，你千萬別因此沮喪。
Gregory, you mustn't let this depress you.
沮喪是一種奢侈，
Depression is a luxury
經驗豐富的精神科醫生是不能沉溺其中的。
not permitted the experienced psychiatrist.
嗯，那很好。
Well, that's good.
因爲這件事也有積極的一面。
Because there is a bright side to this whole thing.
按我那時婚姻的走向來看，
Well, the way my marriage was headed
以及我那時的神經狀態，
and the state of nerves I was in,
要不是有竊盜癖在，我
if it hadn't been for kleptomania
可能真會有點兒精神失常。
I might have gone a little kook.
Penny，你知道當你的分析師有多難嗎？
Penny, do you have any idea how difficult
你知道嗎，做你的分析師可不容易。
it is being your analyst?
哦，Gregory，你應該在認識我之前就見過我，
Oh, Gregory, you should have known me
那時候的我
in the days before you knew me.
很模糊、很輕浮。
I was vague, frivolous.
你甚至可以說我有點兒神經質。
You might even say a bit of a ding.
謝天謝地，我已經安定下來了。再見。
Thank heaven, I've settled down. Bye.
你認爲忘鞋子意味着什麼呢？
What do you suppose it means
當你老是忘記鞋子時，這意味着什麼？嗯。
when you keep forgetting your shoes? Hm.
你要急到哪裏去？你還有七分鐘。
Where are you rushing to? You still have seven minutes left.
哦，你可以記在賬上。我得去 Park Lane 畫廊了。
Oh, you can owe me. I'm off to the park Lane galleries.
那裏有一幅倫勃朗，簡直是撿便宜。
There's a Rembrandt there that's a steal.
倫勃朗。Penny，你不會真的去偷吧。
A Rembrandt. Penny, you wouldn't.
出租車！出租車！
Taxi! Taxi!
噓。
Psst.
Gregory。噓！
Gregory. Shh!
什麼？警察來了。
What? Police.
他們可能跟蹤我來了。警察？
They may have followed me. Police?
Gregory，你到底做了什麼？
Gregory, what have you done?
什麼都沒做。我什麼都沒做。
Nothing. I haven't done anything.
好吧，如果你什麼都沒做，
Well, if you haven't done anything
那警察爲什麼會——
then why would the police...
Penelope，我現在不想爭論。現在告訴我，你把錢藏在哪兒了？
Penelope, I don't want to get into a discussion, not now.
現在告訴我，你把錢藏在哪兒了？
Now tell me, where, where did you hide the money?
什麼錢？
What money?
你說“什麼錢”是什麼意思？你知道的……
What do you mean, what money? You know what...
贓款。那筆贓款。
Loot. The loot.
哦，那個錢。
Oh, that money.
說實話，那事讓我很擔心。
Well, frankly, that's had me very worried.
我的意思是，我不能就把它隨便放在某個地方。
I mean, I couldn't just leave it lying around any place.
你知道的，那樣很不安全。
You know, that could be very dodgy.
我一直隨身帶着……哦！
I carry it with... oh!
你們的中尉 Bixbee 知道了。
Your lieutenant Bixbee, he knows.
他剛來見過我。
He just came to see me.
我覺得他昨天舉止有些奇怪。
I thought he acted strangely yesterday.
奇怪？怎麼奇怪？
Strangely how?
我也說不上來。有點……內疚的樣子。
I don't know. Sort of... guilty.
他爲什麼會覺得內疚？哦，算了。噢！
Why would he feel guilty? Oh, never mind. Ooh!
Penny，聽我說。
Penny, listen to me.
你必須今天就把那筆錢送回銀行。
You've got to get that money back to the bank today.
現在。怎麼做？
Now. How?
我不能就走進去把錢交上去。
I can't just walk in and hand it over.
嗯，我想過……
Well, I figured that...
哦，把錢給我吧，
Oh, give me the money
我會把它放進夜間存款口。
and I'll, I'll stick it in the night deposit chute.
哦，Gregory，我不想你牽扯進來。
Oh, Gregory, I don't like to see you get involved.
我也不想。
Neither do I.
來吧，把所有的都給我。
Come on. All of it.
哦，Penny。
Oh, penny.
Penny.
- 好了，我看起來如何？
- 看起來很害怕。
- Alright, how do I look? - Frightened.
哦，不，我是說頭部這兒。
Oh, no, I mean up here.
- 像蝙蝠俠。 - 謝謝。
- Like Batman. - Thanks.
Gregory，你真體貼。
Gregory, you're very sweet.
但你爲什麼非要這麼做不可？
But why do you insist on doing this?
因爲我愛你。
Because I'm in love with you.
因爲我對你癡狂。 - Gregory.
- Because I'm crazy about you. - Gregory.
當我說癡狂時，我是醫學上說的那種。
And when I say crazy, I'm using the word medically.
- 但就在前幾天…… - 算了。
- But just the other day... - Forget it.
- 你說了…… - 算了，算了！
- You said... - Forget it. Forget it!
現在我們走吧，儘量表現得很自然。
Now let's get out of here and try to act very natural.
- 他們把我們鎖起來了！ - 別擔心。
- They locked us in! - Don't worry.
那鈴鐺應該會有人來。
That bell ought to bring somebody.
那鈴鐺會把所有人都引來。那是盜賊警報。
That bell will bring everybody. That's a burglar alarm.
- 要是他們搜我們怎麼辦？ - 那又怎樣？
- What if they search us? - Well, what of it?
- 我們沒有偷東西。 - 今天沒偷東西。
- We haven't stolen anything. - Not today, we haven't.
你以爲這是什麼地方？
What do you think this is?
- 哦，Penny。 - 他們不敢搜我們。
- Oh, penny. - They wouldn't dare search us.
喂喂，有人在嗎？喂！
Yoo-hoo, somebody! Yoo-hoo!
還不行！還不行！
Not yet! Not yet!
喂！喂！
Yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
晚上好。你介意開門嗎？
Good evening. Would you mind opening the gate, please?
你們在裏面，幹什麼呢？
You in there, what are you up to?
什麼也沒幹。我發誓。
Nothing. I swear it.
請叫經理來。
Please call the manager.
我就是經理。
I am the manager.
關門時你們藏在哪裏了？
Where were you hiding when we locked up?
哦，就在那個櫥櫃後面。
Oh, right behind that cabinet.
不，我們沒有。我們沒藏。
No, we weren't. We weren't hiding.
我們站着，我們站着。
We were standing. We were standing.
你們不知道我們已經關門了嗎？
Don't you realize we're closed?
那正是問題所在。
Well, that's just the trouble.
如果你們開門，我們就能離開。
If you were open, we could leave.
別你們敢搜我們的身
And don't you dare try to search us
否則我們就報警。
or we'll call the police.
Penelope！她不是那個意思。
Penelope! She didn't mean that.
你不是那個意思。
You didn't mean that.
你算什麼，女士？有毛病嗎？
What are you, lady? Some kind of a nut?
我不喜歡你的態度。
I don't care for your attitude.
順便說一句，你見到
And for your information, you have seen
我這種人，這就是最後一次了。
the last of me in this gallery.
走吧，Gregory。
Come, Gregory.
早安，親愛的。喂。是的。
Morning, darling. Hello. Yeah.
嗯。
Yeah.
是的。
Yes.
什麼？你確定嗎？
What? You sure?
是的，我——真難相信。
Yeah, I-I find that hard to believe.
半小時後。
In, uh, half an hour.
好。
Right.
剛纔電話是誰的？
Who was that on the phone?
是銀行打來的。
The bank.
哦，他們想要什麼？
Oh, what'd they want?
誰想要什麼？
What did who want?
銀行。
The bank.
他們想和我談。
They wanted to talk to me.
- 關於什麼 - 關於銀行業的事。
- Well, what about? - About banking.
哦。
Oh.
好吧，他們把金融版放哪兒了？
Well, where did they hide the financial section?
你什麼時候開始關心錢的事了？
Since when have you been concerned with money matters?
我只是表示一點做妻子的關心。
I'm just showing a little wifely interest.
嗯，那真好笑。金融版嗎？
Well, that's funny. The financial section?
不，我只是希望……
No, I was just hoping...
- 早上好，Toshi。 - 早
- Morning, Toshi. - Morning.
我只是想也許會有
I just thought maybe there might be
關於那起搶劫案的一些好消息。
some good news about the robbery.
壞消息怎麼會有好消息？
How can there be good news about bad news?
嗯，有可能。你可能能把錢要回來。
Well, it's possible. You could get the money back.
那不會在財經版出現。
That wouldn't be in the financial section.
會登在宗教版的“奇蹟”欄目。
It would be on the religious page under miracles.
不過，你已經拿回那1000美元了。
Well, you already got that $1000 back.
希望我別用同樣的方式把其餘的錢也拿回來。
Let's hope I don't get the rest back the same way.
我可能會破產。
I could go broke.
James，你還是不明白那件事，不是嗎...
James, you still don't understand about that, do you...
現在我明白了，我明白了，我明白了。
Now I do, I do, I do.
好了，拜託，別再解釋了。
Now, please, don't explain it again.
我收支相抵了，我很高興，我欣喜若狂，是吧？
I broke even, I'm delighted, I'm delirious, huh?
嗯，你確實是收支平衡了。嗯。
Well, you did break even. Mm.
Mannix 醫生說你只是固執罷了。
Dr. Mannix says you're just being stubborn.
哦，Mannix 醫生這麼說的？
Oh, Dr. Mannix says that, does he?
是的，他說了。
Yes, he does.
Mannix 醫生怎麼會知道這事？
How does Dr. Mannix know anything about it?
嗯，因爲我告訴了他。
Well, I told him.
我告訴他一切。
I tell him everything.
什麼？一切？
What do you mean, everything?
一切。
Everything.
關於我也告訴了嗎？
About me too?
當然。
Well, of course.
我想我會去和你的 Mannix 醫生談談。
I think I'll have a talk with your Dr. Mannix.
James，那太好了。
James, that's marvelous.
你無法想象他能幫到你多少。
You have no idea how much he could help you.
我不想要幫助。
I don't want help.
那爲何要浪費錢？
Well, then why waste the money?
Bixbee 中尉。
Lieutenant Bixbee.
你們的錢...
Your money...
我們都找回來了。
We got it all back.
我就知道。
I knew it.
看來我低估你了，Bixbee。
Seems I underestimated you, Bixbee.
我想請你去局裏一趟。
I thought maybe you'd like to go down to headquarters.
你看，我們也抓到了偷錢的那個女孩。
You see, we also got the girl who stole it.
我們現在要把她帶去審問。
We're bringing her up for questioning now.
Toshi，我的帽子！
Toshi, my hat!
我不明白。
I don't understand.
嗯，你知道嗎，這事也讓我有些意外。
Well, you know, it kind of took me by surprise too.
我以爲我把案子想透了。
I thought I had this case all figured out.
- 準備好。- 好了，中尉。
- Goes to show you. - Ready, lieutenant.
等一下，James，我要跟你一起去。
Wait a minute. James, I'll go with you.
不，不，親愛的，你沒必要捲進這件事。
No, no, darling, there's no need for you to be involved in this.
等我！等我！
Wait for me! Wait for me!
Horatio，如果你們逮錯人怎麼辦？
Horatio, what if you've arrested the wrong girl?
絕無可能。
Not a chance.
我們抓她的時候，她身上就有那筆錢。
She had the money on her when we picked her up.
好吧。往這邊來。
Alright. Right this way.
哦，嗨，寶貝。
Oh, hi, doll.
你是新來的嗎，不是嗎？
Well, you're new in here, aren't you?
我是說，我不記得在夜間法庭見過你。
I mean, I don't recall making your acquaintance
in night court or nothin'.
我叫 Honeysuckle Rose。
Mine's honeysuckle Rose.
看起來你過得不錯。
You must be doing pretty good.
那件看起來差點像是真的貂皮。
That almost looks like for-real mink.
好了，Rose小姐。別動，放鬆一下。
Alright, miss Rose. Just hold it. Relax a minute.
不是冒犯您，Elcott太太。
No offense, Mrs. Elcott.
那穿真貂皮的女士是這位先生的太太，
The lady in the genuine mink is the wife of this gentleman,
正好是你們被搶的那家銀行的行長。
who happens to be the president of the bank that you hit.
哦。
Oh.
她看起來確實有點像…
Well, she looks pretty enough to be...
你真名叫什麼，親愛的？
What's your right name, honey?
我不是跟你說了嗎，Honeysuckle Rose。
Well, I told you. Honeysuckle Rose.
我姐姐叫 Mexicali Rose。
My sister's Mexicali Rose.
我知道，都是 Washington Square 的那些“玫瑰”。
I know, the roses of Washington square.
Huntington，West Virginia。
Huntington, West Virginia.
我們曾經開車經過那裏，James，還記得嗎？
We drove through there once, James, remember?
Penelope，拜託。我們能繼續了嗎？
Penelope, please. Can't we get on with this, hm?
Honeysuckle，你能不能做個乖孩子
Honeysuckle, why don't you be a good girl
好好把話說清楚，坦白承認？
and just give us a full confession?
嗯，好吧。
Hm, okay.
呃，我昨晚在 Park Avenue 遛貓
Um, I was walking my cat up park Avenue
大約，呃，凌晨三點左右
around, uh, 3 o'clock this morning
我看到那東西幾乎就躺在人行道上。
when I see that lying on the sidewalk... practically.
更正一下。你是走進了我的銀行
Correction. You walked into my bank
大約下午3點左右
around 3 o'clock in the afternoon
兩天前，偷走了那筆錢。
two days ago and stole the money.
等會兒。
Now wait a minute.
我看起來像會搶銀行的人嗎？
Do I look like a person who'd stick up a bank?
當然不是。
Of course not.
哎呦，凌晨三點遛貓有什麼不對嗎？
Oh, come now, walking a cat at 3 o'clock in the morning?
我看不出有什麼不對。
I don't see anything wrong with that.
她可能做的是夜班工作。
She probably does night work.
- 你是嗎？ - 嗯，呃……
- Do you? - Well, uh...
是的。
Yeah.
看吧？
You see?
好吧，事情總算定下來了。
Well, I'm glad we got that decided.
Penelope，我覺得你並沒有看清全貌。
Penelope, I don't think you're getting the full picture.
你看，對 Rose 小姐的指控
You see, the charge against miss Rose here
不是遛貓，而是搶銀行。
is not cat-walking, it's bank-robbing.
這是陷害。
Well, it's a frame.
我發誓我從沒進過那家銀行。
I never set foot inside that bank, I swear it.
我相信你。
I believe you.
但他們不信。
Well, but they don't.
看看他們的表情！
Well, look at their faces!
哦，這可不是30天服刑就完事的案子。
Oh, this is no 30 days and out rap.
他們要把我關起來，扔掉鑰匙。
They-they wanna lock me up and throw away the key.
親愛的，相信我，你堅持這個荒謬的說法只會讓自己更難受
Honey, believe me, you're only making it tough on yourself
一直堅持這種荒唐的故事。
by sticking to this cockamamie story.
那是我唯一會編的荒誕故事！
Well, that's the only cockamamie story I know!
好了，女管理員，把她帶出去。
Alright, matron, get her out of here.
哦，不，等等。
Oh, no. No, wait.
等等，我…我承認。
Wait, I-I-l admit it.
我撒謊了。
Lied.
那錢並不是放在路邊的。
The-the money w-wasn't on the sidewalk.
是從存款口裏露出來的。
I-it was sticking out of the deposit slot.
本來我是要把它送回去的，或許還能拿點賞金。
Well, I was gonna return it. Maybe collect a reward even.
但那不會讓我成了搶銀行的壞人，對吧？
But that doesn't make me a bank robber, does it?
我是說，不是他們所說的那種意思。
I mean, not-not like they mean.
等等，等等。
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你們犯了個可怕的錯誤。
You're making a terrible mistake.
親愛的，他們知道自己在做什麼。
Honey, they know what they're doing.
那你怎麼知道她沒有說實話？
Well, how do you know that she isn't telling the truth?
這是我的推測。事情完全可能按她說的那樣發生過。
It's my theory. It could have happened exactly as she said it.
你是說有人真的把59,000美元
You mean somebody actually left $59,000
在深夜放在銀行門口？
on the doorstep of a bank in the middle of the night?
- 是的！ - 誰，Elcott太太？
- Yes! - Who, Mrs. Elcott?
小偷，就是那人。搶銀行的那位。
The thief, that's who. The bank robber.
親愛的，出於什麼理由呢？
For what possible reason, darling?
因爲她想擺脫那筆錢。
Because she was trying to get rid of it.
在她從中偷走錢的同一家銀行裏？
In the same bank that she stole it from?
當然。
Certainly.
你看，她從來就不想要那錢。
You see, she never wanted the money in the first place.
- 她之所以拿走是因爲... - 爲什麼？
- She only took it because... - Because why?
因爲她控制不了自己。
Because she couldn't help herself.
呃，Elcott太太，我們感謝你的幫助，
Uh, we appreciate your help, Mrs. Elcott,
但你的理論是出於對嫌疑人的同情，
but your theory is based on sympathy for the suspect,
而不是事實。
not fact.
好了，女管理員。
Okay, matron.
不！
No!
好吧。
Alright.
你們想要供詞，我會確保你們得到一個。
You wanted a confession and I'll see that you get one.
非常感謝，但 Rose小姐不願意說話。
Thanks a lot, but miss Rose is not talking.
不是從 Rose小姐那裏，是從真正的搶劫犯那裏。
No, not from miss Rose, from the bank robber.
就是那個搶你們銀行的女人
From the woman who robbed your bank
戴着紅色假髮、穿黃色套裝逃走的那位。
and escaped in a red wig and a yellow suit.
我。
Me.
對不起，James。
I'm sorry, James.
改天我再解釋爲什麼非得選你們的銀行。
I'll just have to explain later why it had to be your bank.
但現在最重要的是
But right now, the most important thing
揪出事實真相
is to get to the truth of this
這樣這個可憐的無辜女孩就不必入獄。
so that this poor innocent girl doesn't have to go to jail.
所以請叫個速記員來吧，
So if you will call a stenographer
我會口述一份完整的陳述。
I will dictate a full statement.
現在，Elcott太太，我擔心你有些緊張過度。
Now, Mrs. Elcott, I'm afraid you're under a strain.
或許你最好把她送回家。
Perhaps you better take her home.
你知道，打個盹什麼的。
You know, a nap or somethin'.
你們不相信我嗎？
Why, you don't believe me.
你們任何人都不相信。
None of you.
當真相就擺在你面前時，你們都看不出來。
You don't recognize the truth when it slaps you in the face.
你覺得我瘋了嗎，不是嗎？
You think I'm crazy, don't you?
哦，不，當然不是。不是。
Oh, no, certainly not. No.
呃，你知道，有時候，呃……
Uh, you know, sometimes, uh...
嗯，我們有時都需要幫助。
Well, we all need help sometimes.
嗯，我並不處於緊張狀態。
Well, I am not under a strain.
至於我的頭腦，從來沒有
And as far as my head, it has never been
像此刻這般清晰。
clearer than at this moment.
至於我是否需要幫助，
And as far as my needing help is concerned,
讓我向你保證：我每週都見精神科醫生五次。
let me assure you that I see my psychiatrist five times a week.
女管理員。
Matron.
對不起，Rose小姐。
I'm sorry, miss Rose.
但別擔心，他們不會關你太久。
But don't worry, they can't keep you long.
我會讓他們相信我。我向你保證。
I'll make them believe me. I promise you.
謝謝。
Thank you.
但是——你知道嗎，Elcott太太，
But-but you know something, Mrs. Elcott,
呃——這真可惜，
a-and it's a shame,
就連我也不相信你。
even I don't believe you.
我可憐的寶貝。
My poor darling.
哦，James，我真失望。
Oh, I'm so disappointed in you, James.
你爲什麼不相信我？
Why won't you believe me?
相信你是竊盜癖患者？小偷？銀行劫匪？
Believe you're a kleptomaniac? A thief? A bank robber?
親愛的，你會那樣看我嗎？
Darling, would you believe that of me?
當然會。
Of course.
如果你真心想讓我相信你是小偷，我會相信的。
If you really and truly wanted me
to believe that you were a thief, I would.
- 因爲我信任你。 - 我怎麼能相信你？
- Because I trust you. - How can I believe you?
昨晚三點鐘
Last night at 3:00 in the morning
你還躺在我身旁。
you were in bed next to me.
那又有什麼問題？我們是夫妻。
Well, what's wrong with that? We're married.
嗯，但——那筆錢，親愛的。
Uh, but-but the money, darling.
哦，那件事。
Oh, that.
Gregory 替我把錢放回去了。
Gregory took it back for me.
我得說他做得並不怎麼好。
I must say he didn't do a very good job of it.
他並沒有在幫助你這件事上做得很好
He's not doing a very good job of helping you
通過遷就你這些幻想。
by humoring these fantasies of yours.
你知道 Gregory 爲什麼說我搶了你們銀行嗎？
Do you know why Gregory says I robbed your bank?
因爲你把更多注意力放在銀行上，而不是我身上。
Because you pay more attention to it than you do to me.
你幾乎都不再注意我了。
You hardly ever even notice me anymore.
我知道。我能做什麼？告訴我你想要什麼。
You know I do. What do you want? Tell me what you want.
任何事，任何你想要的，親愛的。
Anything, anything you want, darling.
好吧，真正讓我在意的只有一件事。
Well, there's only one thing I really care about.
那件事對我很重要。
Something that would mean a great deal to me.
說吧。
Name it.
我想舉辦一個體面的雞尾酒會
I'd like to give a nice cocktail party
爲你所有的朋友舉行。
for all of your friends.
一個雞尾酒會。
A cocktail party.
你要不要讓司機把你放在銀行門口？
Should you tell the driver to drop you off at the bank?
穿這身？
In this?
她在家嗎？Elcott 太太？
She's home? Mrs. Elcott?
請問誰打來？
Who is calling, please?
朋友。
Friends.
匿名的。
Anonymous.
匿名先生和太太。
Mr. and Mrs. anonymous.
你好。
Hello.
- 你記得 Sadaba 嗎？ - 還有 Ducky？
- You remember Sadaba? - And ducky?
當然記得。
Of course.
請坐，Elcott 太太。
Have a seat, Mrs. Elcott.
我有什麼能爲你效勞的嗎？
Is there something I can do for you?
- 爲我們？不。 - 我們要爲你做點事。
- For us? No. - We do something for you.
哦，我在等客人。
Oh, well, I'm expecting guests.
呃，如果你們是來賣衣服的...
Uh, if you're here to sell me a dress...
重要得多，不只是件衣服。
Much more important than a dress.
我們來賣給你自由。
We come to sell you freedom.
哦！那真是個了不起的事業。
Oh! Oh, well, that's a wonderful cause.
我一直對自由很感興趣。
I'm always interested in freedom.
- 爲所有人。 - 尤其是爲你。
- For everybody. - Especially for you.
現在說說錢。
The check now.
你想要多少？
How much would you like?
25000 美元。
Twenty-five thousand dollars.
要這麼多？
As much as that?
那是用來幹什麼的？
Well, what, uh, is it for?
爲了讓一位好女士不進監獄。
To keep a nice lady out of jail.
Sadaba 知道 Mrs. James Elcott 搶了她丈夫的銀行。
Sadaba knows Mrs. James Elcott robbed her husband's bank.
你知道這事？
You know that?
真的？你確定嗎？
Really? Are you positive?
你沒剛剛聽見她自己承認嗎？
You didn't hear her just tell you?
你能證明嗎？
Can you prove it?
Sadaba 是傻瓜嗎？
Is Sadaba a fool?
她當場就證明了。怎麼證明？
Certainly she proves it. How?
這是兩年前雜誌上的一張照片。
Here is a picture from magazine two years old.
你認出這位女士了嗎？
You recognize the lady?
- 是我！- 哦，別靠那麼近。
- It's me! - Oh, not so close.
Ducky，親愛的，讀上面的字。
Ducky, sweetheart, read the words.
“在慈善午宴上，紐約的 Mrs. James Elcott
"At luncheon for charity, Mrs. James Elcott of New York
身着 Givenchy 設計的黃色羊毛套裝。”
wearing a suit of yellow wool designed by Givenchy."
那就是穿黃色套裝的我！
It's me in the yellow suit!
如果有人看到了那...
Well, if anybody saw that...
你們在勒索我！
You're blackmailing me!
勒索是刑事犯罪。
Blackmail is a criminal offense.
我們的目的是
What we're trying to do
做一件價值 25000 美元的好事。
is a $25,000 good turn.
哦。
Oh.
如果我不付呢？
And suppose I won't pay it?
那你會付的，否則我們就把照片給你丈夫看。
But you will, or we show this to your husband.
哦，我能指望你們這麼做嗎？
Oh, can I depend on that?
算是我的承諾。
Here is my word.
她說的“指望”是什麼意思？
What does she mean, depend on it?
哦，他隨時會來。
Oh, he ought to be along any minute.
你能等嗎？
Can you wait?
也許丈夫也牽涉其中，是吧？
So maybe the husband is in the game, huh?
那我們甚至可以不用給他看？
So maybe we don't even bother to show him?
哦，你們一定要的，拜託。
Oh, you've got to, please.
我們沒有......
We don't got...
但也許我們應該把照片拿去給警察。
But maybe we take the picture to the police.
立刻。快點。
Right away. Quick.
你覺得怎麼樣？
What do you say to that?
好，我-我就跟你們去。
Okay, I-I'll go with you.
不。
No.
Ducky，這地方讓我覺得有點可疑。
Ducky, something is smelling crooked in the place.
- 出去。 - 不！哦，等等！拜託，聽我說！
- Out. - No! Oh, wait! Please, listen!
- 我們把證據處理掉！- 停下！你們在幹什麼？
- We get rid of the evidence! - Stop! What are you doing?
拜託，你們把一切都毀了！
Please, you're spoiling everything!
我們把證據吞了！吞下去！
We swallow the evidence! Swallow!
James，哦，親愛的。
James, oh, darling.
幸好你來了。
Thank heaven you're here.
親愛的，這是 Princess Sadaba 和 Ducky。
Darling, this is Princess Sadaba and Ducky.
他們來這裏是想勒索我。
And they came here to blackmail me.
Princess Sadaba，現在請向我丈夫解釋
Princess Sadaba, now please explain to my husband
爲什麼你要勒索我。
why you're blackmailing me.
我們是來給你太太看晚禮服的。
We came to interest your wife in an evening gown.
突然之間，居然有人跟我說起
Out of the blue, suddenly I'm hearing
呃，勒索的事。
uh, about blackmail.
James, 那不是真的
James, that's not true.
他們有確鑿的證據說我搶了你們的銀行。
They have positive proof that I robbed your bank.
什麼銀行？
What bank?
Mr. Elcott，很抱歉這麼說，
Mr. Elcott, I hate to say this,
但你娶了個有點古怪的女人。
but you are married to some wacky woman.
我妻子最近一直覺得不太好。
My wife has not been feeling too well lately.
James，你要相信他們還是相信我？
James, are you going to believe them or me?
親愛的，你又在幻想了。
Honey, you're imagining things again.
幻想？幻想？
Imagining things? Imagining things?
好吧，問他他在吃什麼。
Alright, ask him what he's eating.
打擾一下，先生，你在吃什麼？
Excuse me, sir, what are you eating?
- 我吃得晚了。 - 謝謝。
- I had a late lunch. - Thank you.
哦！
Oh!
來吧，殿下。
Come, highness.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
如果我能彌補什麼的話……
If there's any way I can make amends...
你有沒有氣泡水之類的？
You got maybe a little seltzer?
出去！
Out!
James，多麼有趣的聚會啊。
James, such a fun party.
你的Penelope什麼時候出來？
When's your Penelope going to appear?
也許她拉鍊卡住了。我去看看。
Maybe she's having zipper trouble. I'll just go and see.
Mannix 醫生。
Dr. Mannix.
我不知道精神病醫生會上門看病。
I didn't know a psychiatrist made house calls.
我是個客人。
I am a guest.
我還有請柬，看到了嗎？
And I have an invitation. See?
你有過。現在沒有了。
You did. Now you don't.
那不是挺孩子氣的做法嗎？
Isn't that a rather childish thing to do?
那來點更成熟的怎麼樣？
Then how about something more grownup?
比如，給你一拳鼻子怎麼樣？
Say, a punch in the nose?
把你身上的怒氣發泄到我身上對你沒用。
Taking out your aggressions on me is not going to help you.
對你沒用，但你也幫不了我妻子。
It won't help you, but then you're not helping my wife.
我只負責這案子三年，先生。
I've only been on the case for three years, sir.
到這段時間結束時，你的病人，你以前的病人
At the end of which time, your patient, your former patient
比起開始時更糟了。
is worse off than when she first started with you.
以前的？你說以前的是什麼意思？我不明白。
Former? W-W-What do you mean by, uh, former? I don't understand.
那我來解釋。你被解僱了。
Then I'll explain. You're fired.
等等！Elcott，你不能那樣！
Wait! Elcott, you can't do that!
Penny。Penny？
Penny. Penny?
嗯，有事嗎？
Yes, what is it?
大家都在找你，親愛的。你要出來嗎？
Everyone's asking for you, honey. Are you coming out?
我告訴過你，要的。
I told you, yes.
什麼時候？
When?
等Mildred Halliday來了我就出來。
As soon as Mildred Halliday gets here.
Mildred Halliday和這有什麼關係？
What's Mildred Halliday got to do with it?
你會看到的。
You'll see.
Penny，讓我進去我們談談，好嗎？
Penny, just let me in and we'll talk it over, huh?
Penny，如果你能回答我就好了。
Penny, if you'll just answer me.
Penny，開門！
Penny, open!
這個門把有點卡。哦。
This knob, it sticks. Oh.
- 我得找個螺絲刀。- 嗯哼。
- I have to get a screwdriver. - Mm-hmm.
你應該在黃頁裏找找。
Well, you should try to find it in the yellow pages.
或者打開我的門。
Or open my door.
你好，Mildred。歡迎來參加聚會。
Hello, Mildred. Welcome to the party.
哦，James，確保Mildred得到她想要的一切。
Oh, James, make sure Mildred gets everything she wants.
- 哦，可憐的親愛的。- 哦，Mildred。
- Oh, poor darling. - Oh, Mildred.
你能幫我一個忙嗎？
Would you mind doing me a favor?
哦，任何事，任何事。
Oh, anything, anything.
試着換個人親一下，行嗎？
Try kissing somebody else for a change, huh?
說真的，我確實有親，
Well, honestly, I do,
但我就是不那麼享受了。
but I just don't enjoy it as much.
一杯雙份蘇格蘭威士忌。蘇打還是加冰？
A double scotch. Soda or over the rocks?
再來一杯雙份蘇格蘭威士忌。
Over another double scotch.
哦，真美味，我敬這一杯。
Ooh, yummy, I'll drink to that.
晚上好。晚上好。
Good evening. Good evening.
晚上好，James。
Good evening, James.
Penny，這都是怎麼回事？你會看的。
Penny, what's all this? You'll see.
親愛的Heller小姐，很高興你能來。
Dear miss Heller, so good of you to come.
你最近有看到什麼好游泳池的底部嗎？
Have you seen the bottom of any good swimming pools lately?
搞錯了？我……
Mistaken? I...
Daphne。Daphne，親愛的。
Daphne. Daphne, darling.
下次你去跳迪斯科的時候，要小心點。
The next time you go discothequeing, you should be more careful.
你把你的王冠弄丟了。
You lost your tiara.
James，這是她的惡作劇嗎？
James, is this her idea of a joke?
Penny，親愛的，進來吧。
Penny darling, come inside.
Mildred，不知爲什麼
Mildred, for some reason
他們似乎不想把首飾要回去。
they don't seem to want their jewelry back.
但我確定你會的。
But I'm sure you will.
我婚禮那天的紀念物。
A memento of my wedding day.
親愛的 Penelope，你總是
Dear Penelope, you always did
有那麼古怪的幽默感。
have such a quaint sense of humor.
我這輩子從沒見過那些綠寶石。
I never saw those emeralds in my life.
- Mildred！ - Penny，求你了。
- Mildred! - Penny, please.
James，有些不對勁。
James, something's wrong.
非常嚴重的不對勁。
Something's terribly wrong.
我很害怕。
I'm frightened.
Penelope，等等！
Penelope, wait!
- Penelope！ Penelope，等等！ - Jimmy，讓她走。
- Penelope! Penelope, wait! - Jimmy, let her go.
她知道自己出醜了，感到很尷尬。
She knows she's made a fool of herself and she's embarrassed.
- 我得阻止她。
- 哦，如果你阻止她你會後悔的。
- I've got to stop her. - Oh, you'll be sorry if you do.
如果我不阻止她，我會後悔。
I'll be sorry if I don't.
整晚。
All night long.
我跟你說我擔心得要命。
I tell you I'm frantic with worry.
如果你想起什麼...
If you think of anything...
很明顯她覺得你辜負了她。
Well, it's obvious she thinks you've failed her.
她很困惑。
She's confused.
而在她的困惑中
And in her confusion
她會轉向她唯一信任的人。
she'll turn to the one person she can trust.
就是我。冷靜點，Elcott。
Yours truly. Just calm down, Elcott.
我們正在盡一切努力。
We're doing everything we can.
如果你妻子覺得有危險，
If your wife feels in any danger,
無冒犯之意，她會來找我尋求保護。
no offense, it's me that she'll come to for protection.
Serena 小姐。
Miss Serena.
- 哦，多甜的名字。 - 謝謝。
- Oh, what a sweet name. - Thank you.
我總認爲名字有很大影響...
I always think that names have a great influence...
你以爲是誰... 哎呦！
Who do you think... ow!
好，讓我來... 小心。
Alright, let me... watch out.
我不怕你，你這個大惡霸。
I'm not afraid of you, you big bully.
一個老太太拿走...（這個主意）
The idea of an old woman taking a...
可恥！
Shame on you!
防碎的，哈！
Shatterproof, ha!
把那該死的東西關掉！
Shut that damn thing off!
謝謝。
Thank you.
啊，我的可育雞蛋和酸奶。我要告你。
Oh, my fertile eggs and my yogurt. I'll sue you.
現在看看是誰戴着這張可笑的面具。
Now let's see who's under this ridiculous-looking mask.
她給我十塊錢的時候可沒提過要捏鼻子這事。
She didn't say nothin' about nose-tweaking
她給我十塊錢的時候可沒提過。
when she give me the ten bucks.
她？誰？
She? Who?
她說是個惡作劇，我信了她。
A practical joke, she said, and I believed her.
她那雙又大又悲傷的褐色眼睛，
Her with those big, sad brown eyes,
她還能那麼會哭。
and how she could cry.
她長什麼樣？
What did she look like?
年輕、漂亮，穿着白色晚禮服，
Young, pretty, white evening gown
大概就是這樣子。
and about so big.
Penelope。
Penelope.
- 哦！ - 親愛的，是我。
- Oh! - Darling, it's me.
不是你。
It isn't you.
我們被搶了。就在後面，當我們都在這兒的時候。
We've been robbed. Back there while we were all up here.
Penelope。
Penelope.
Elcott，等一下。
Elcott, wait a minute.
我知道。跟着那輛出租車。
I know. Follow the cab.
不，不，我在找一個女孩。
No, no, I'm looking for a girl.
誰不是？
Who ain't?
她應該剛從銀行出來。
And she'd have just come out of the bank.
- 甩得很迷人？ - 是的，是的。
- With a real nice wiggle? - Yes, yes.
她，她，她往哪邊走了？
Which, which-which way did she go?
往市區方向。
Downtown.
往市區？
Downtown?
你盯着什麼看，Mac？
What you starin' at, Mac?
那張臉。
That face.
哦，剛纔那一刻，你看起來就像我太太。
Oh, for-for a moment, you looked just like my wife.
我還以爲我娶的是條狗。
And I thought mine was a dog.
你說往市區？
Downtown, you said?
呃，帶我去中心街，警察局總部。
Uh, take me to centre street, police headquarters.
Penelope？
Penelope?
我說得對。你來找我了。
I was right. You came to me.
我還能去找誰？
Who else would I come to?
你要我先走嗎，不等你？
You want me to go ahead without you?
聽着，你不會相信的，
Listen, you're not gonna believe this,
可有人剛搶了你丈夫的銀行。
but somebody just knocked over your husband's bank.
嗯，你可能不信，但我信你。
Well, you won't believe this, but I believe you.
你搶了你丈夫的銀行？
You robbed your husband's bank?
不止一次。兩次。
Twice.
中士，我剛破了 Elcott 案。
Sergeant, I just solved the Elcott case.
長大後我想當個像你這樣的警察。
When I grow up, I wanna be a cop just like you.
你現在得放了 Honeysuckle，是吧？
You'll have to release honeysuckle now, won't you?
以童子軍的名譽發誓。
Scout's honor.
我來了，我來了。
I'm going, I'm going.
嗯，我想我們可能不會再見面了。
Well, I, uh, I guess we won't be seeing one another anymore.
你們不會要逮捕我嗎？
Aren't you gonna arrest me?
除非銀行行長提出起訴，
Not unless the bank president presses charges,
否則幾乎不太可能。
which is hardly likely.
謝謝你，Horatio。
Thank you, Horatio.
不客氣，Penelope。
You're welcome, Penelope.
好吧，這段犯罪生涯雖短，但很精彩。
Well, it was a great criminal career while it lasted.
算是最棒的之一。
One of the best.
Elcott 先生，進來吧。
Mr. Elcott, come on in.
我從沒見你在五點之前喝東西。
I've never seen you take a drink before 5:00.
總有地方是五點鐘。
It's gotta be 5:00 someplace.
可你不是 Penelope。
But you're not Penelope.
聽到了嗎？
Hear that?
這個人居然把他妻子送去看瘋醫生。
And this guy sends his wife to the crazy doctor.
我不認爲威士忌是你的解藥。
I don't think whisky's your answer.
Gregory。
Gregory.
Gregory？
Gregory?
我告訴他你會來找我。
I told him you would turn to me.
哦，我還能去找誰呢？
Oh, who else could I turn to?
感謝上天你平安無事。
Thank heaven you're safe and sound.
安全但不正常。
Safe but not sound.
Gregory，我真的很害怕。
Gregory, I'm really frightened.
我一定有很嚴重的問題。
There must be something terribly wrong with me.
我的意思是，我就是無法理解
I mean, I just cannot get it through my head
我並沒有真的偷那些珠寶這件事。
that I didn't actually steal all those jewels.
然而我知道我不可能偷。
And yet I know I couldn't have.
你確實偷了那些珠寶。
You did steal the jewels.
他們讓保險公司
They stuck the insurance companies
承擔了這些索賠，吃了大虧，
with their claims but good,
所以自然他們不想要這些東西回去。
so naturally, they didn't want the stuff back.
那我就完全痊癒了。
Then I'm completely cured.
真的嗎？
You are?
是的。我不是告訴過你嗎？
Yes. Didn't I tell you?
我剛又把 James 的銀行搶了一次。
I just finished robbing James' bank again.
可你已經完全康復了？
But you're completely cured?
當然了。
Of course.
因爲當我做那事的時候
Because the whole time I was doing it
我哭得很厲害。
I was crying like anything.
你不明白嗎？
Don't you get it?
看，偷東西不再讓我開心了。
You see, the stealing didn't make me cheerful anymore.
它讓我感覺很糟糕。
It made me feel rotten.
所以這意味着我不是竊盜癖。
So that means I'm not a kleptomaniac.
這不是很好嗎？
Isn't that wonderful?
那真糟糕。
That's terrible.
不再偷東西。不再有愛好。
No more stealing. No more hobbies.
也不再有婚姻。
No more marriage.
只有感到糟糕。
Just feeling rotten.
這好嗎？
Is that wonderful?
接下來怎麼辦？
What next?
嗯，你可以嫁給我。
Well, you could marry me.
我知道這聽起來不道德，
I know it sounds unethical,
而且你可能會難以
and you'd probably have difficulty
把我從父親般的角色調整爲情人形象。
readjusting me from a father figure
把我從父親形象調整爲情人形象。
to a lover image.
而且我可能對你來說太高了。
And I'm probably too tall for you.
太老了。
Too old.
我敢肯定你沒有足夠的壁櫥空間
I'm sure you don't have enough closet space
給我的衣服放在你公寓裏。
for my clothes in your apartment.
我會打呼嚕，而且...
I do snore a lot and...
我有胃潰瘍。
I have this ulcer.
Dr. Knoblock！
Dr. Knoblock!
我需要幫助！
I need help!
Penelope，你怎麼能這樣對我？
How could you do this to me, Penelope?
你知道我受不了被拒絕。
You know I can't stand rejection.
Penelope。
Penelope.
Mannix 醫生。
Dr. Mannix.
呃，你，你得幫我。
Uh, you, you've got to help me.
我看哪裏，眼裏全是 Penelope。
Everywhere I look, all I can see is Penelope.
在銀行、出租車上、在警察局。
In the bank, in the cab, at the police station.
就在剛纔我進來時，
And just now when I came in,
連你在我眼裏也像 Penelope。
even you looked like Penelope to me.
我知道這一切都和愛她、想念她混在一起
I know it's all mixed up with loving her and missing her
還有，那種內疚感
and, and feeling guilty
因爲那家愚蠢的銀行而把她擠到一邊。
about shoving her aside for that stupid bank.
我可能不該把這些無聊事說給你聽。
I probably shouldn't be boring you with all this.
哦，不，別停下來。
Oh, no, don't stop now.
你正說到精彩部分。
You're just getting to the good part.
啊，現在我真的迷失了。
Ah, now I'm really gone.
你甚至聽起來像她。
You even sound like her.
要是有什麼辦法，要是我能找到她
If there was only some way, if I could only find her
告訴她我有多需要她。
and tell her how much I need her.
Mannix 醫生，你需要幫助。
Dr. Mannix, you need help.
現在大家都需要。
Everybody does these days.
唯一不同的是，我們這些適應得較好的人
The only difference is, we well-adjusted
還能及時意識到。
maladjusted ones realize it in time.
而且，最好的幫助
And besides, the best help of all
就是在家裏才能得到的那種幫助。
is the kind you can only get at home.
忘記鞋子意味着什麼？
What does it mean when you forget your shoes?
- 嗯... - 這意味着我們都治好了，親愛的。
- Well... - It means we're cured, darling.
♪ 想象一個生活像瘋狂魔術師的女孩 ♪
♪ Picture a girl whose life is as crazy as a mad magician ♪
♪ 這就是 Penelope ♪ ♪ 這就是 Penelope... ♪
♪ this is Penelope ♪ ♪ this is Penelope... ♪